What can you tell me about this?
关于这件事，您能告诉我些什么？   从
&gt;&gt; Well, if you look at the science, it's
科学角度来看，它能
enhancing cognition. We've seen a 50%
增强认知能力。 我们发现，
improvement in how individuals were able
人们
to read and absorb information of better
阅读和吸收信息的能力提高了 50%，从而能够做出更好的
decision-m and also we did a study and
决策；此外，我们还进行了一项研究，结果
showed that it delayed the progression
表明，这延缓了
of metastatic cancer. And I've actually
转移性癌症的进展。 事实上，我已经
taken this a number of times because
多次服用过这种药物，因为在
having been in research for the last 15
过去的 15 年里我一直从事研究工作，
years and having lived with multiple
并且患有多种
chronic diseases, one of which I
慢性疾病，其中一种我已经
reversed. Some of the most powerful
治愈。 像这样一些最有效的
strategies like this were not being told
策略，
to me when I went to the doctor's
我去医生办公室的时候并没有人告诉我
office. So, let's dig deeper.
。 那么，让我们深入探讨一下。
&gt;&gt; Dr. Andrew Cutnick is a research
Andrew Cutnick 博士是一位研究
scientist who's worked on over 100
科学家，他参与了 100 多项
studies on metabolic health, diabetes,
关于代谢健康、糖尿病
and the keto diet.
和生酮饮食的研究。
&gt;&gt; And through his findings, he's helping
通过他的研究成果，他正在帮助
people prevent chronic diseases, improve
人们预防慢性疾病、改善
cognition, and optimize performance. I
认知能力和优化表现。 我
moments in my childhood. You know, I did
的童年经历了一些非常戏剧性的时刻。 你知道，我把
everything I was told, right? I
吩咐的都做了，对吧？ 我一直
exercised all the time. I ate what I was
坚持锻炼。 我吃了该
supposed to eat, but I still became
吃的食物，但还是
obese.
变胖了。
&gt;&gt; You weighed about 255 lbs.
你的体重约为255磅。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yep. And I had no idea how damaging that
。 我当时完全不知道这会对
actually was to my body. And I think the
我的身体造成多大的伤害。 而且我认为
vast majority of people also don't, but
绝大多数人也不这么认为，但
over 20% of children have obesity.
超过 20% 的儿童患有肥胖症。   过去
That's quadrupled over the last 30
30年里，这个数字增长了四倍
years. And a big part of that is when it
。 其中很大一部分原因是，就
comes to food, what looks healthy isn't
食物而言，看起来很健康的食物并不
always healthy. And it's not by
总是健康的。 这并非
accident. And it wasn't soon after that
偶然。 不久之后，
I ended up getting diagnosed with a
我就被诊断出患有一种
chronic irreversible disease that
慢性不可逆转的疾病，而
obesity puts you at risk for. And that
肥胖会增加患上这种疾病的风险。 于是，这
immediately turned into a journey to
立刻演变成了一段
understand how to be healthy. And I came
了解如何保持健康的旅程。 十多年前，我偶然接触到一种
ago called the ketogenic diet. So then I
叫做生酮饮食的饮食方法。 于是，我
went into the science of this diet and
开始研究这种饮食的科学原理，
found positive impacts on things like
发现它对
diabetes, obesity, Alzheimer's, serious
糖尿病、肥胖症、阿尔茨海默病、严重
mental illness, chronic diseases. And I
精神疾病、慢性疾病等都有积极的影响。 我当时
was like, "Oh wow." Cuz a lot of people
就想，“哇哦。” 因为很多人
don't realize that many of these are not
没有意识到，其中很多问题
just preventable but also reversible.
不仅可以预防，而且是可以逆转的。
And you did the longest study ever done
你进行了迄今为止同类研究中耗时最长的关于
ketogenic diet on a patient that had
生酮饮食对
type 1 diabetes.
1 型糖尿病患者影响的研究。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. Let me let me tell you all about
。 让我来给你详细说说
it.
。
&gt;&gt; I see messages all the time in the
我经常在
comments section that some of you didn't
评论区看到有人留言说他们没有
realize you didn't subscribe. So, if you
意识到自己没有订阅。 所以，如果您
could do me a favor and double check if
能帮我个忙，再次确认一下
you're a subscriber to this channel,
您是否是本频道的订阅者，我
that would be tremendously appreciated.
将万分感激。
It's the simple, it's the free thing
这是件简单又免费的事情，
that anybody that watches this show
任何经常观看本节目的人都
frequently can do to help us here to
可以做，以帮助我们
keep everything going in this show in
保持本节目目前的良好发展
the trajectory it's on. So please do
势头。 所以请您务必
double check if you've subscribed and uh
再次确认是否已订阅，
thank you so much because in a strange
非常感谢，因为从某种意义上说，
way you are you're part of our history
您是我们历史的一部分，
and you're on this journey with us and I
您与我们一起踏上了这段旅程，我
appreciate you for that. So yeah, thank
为此感谢您。 所以，谢谢
you
您，
Dr. Andrew Kutnik. If you had to try and
安德鲁·库特尼克博士。 如果要你尝试
sort of summarize and encapsulate what
总结和概括
you spent the last couple of decades of
你过去二十年所
your life focused on and really trying
专注和努力
to accomplish, prove, understand from
实现、证明、理解的
the highest level. What exactly is that?
最高层次的事情，你会怎么做？ 那到底是什么？
The core of my mission, Stephen, is
斯蒂芬，我的核心使命是
really to empower individuals to take
真正赋予个人掌控
control of their own health. It's
自身健康的能力。 这是
empowering them with science, you know,
用科学赋予他们力量，你知道，就是将
bridging science to actual action. You
科学与实际行动联系起来。 你
know, science is very complex. It's very
知道，科学非常复杂。
hard to break it down, but having been
很难具体解释，但
in, you know, research for the last 15
你知道，过去 15
years and having lived with
年我一直从事研究工作，并且患有
multiple chronic diseases, uh, one of
多种慢性疾病，其中一种
which I reversed and one of which I is
我已经治愈，另一种是
irreversible. Um, I I my mission is to
不可逆转的。 嗯，我的使命是让
empower patients with the same tools and
患者拥有
strategies I had access to. uh so they
我曾经拥有的那些工具和策略。 这样他们
can take control to maximize their
就能掌控自己的健康状况，最大限度地提高
health and performance.
健康和运动表现。
&gt;&gt; For the average person who may not be as
对于不太
knowledgeable about health and fitness,
了解健康和健身的普通人来说，在
spent the last 15 years researching and
过去的 15 年里，您主要研究和
trying to understand?
试图了解哪些健康领域？
&gt;&gt; I would call it, you know, Stephen like
我会把它称为，你知道，斯蒂芬，
metabolism in a broad terms. Now I would
从广义上讲，就像新陈代谢一样。 现在我
say you know to break that down further
想说，为了让人们理解，我们可以进一步解释一下，
for people to understand that metabolism
新陈代谢
is trying to understand how the body
是指了解身体如何
metabolizes or utilizes things like
代谢或利用
nutrients or food. So you have oranges
营养物质或食物等物质。 这里有橙子
here. What's what's in that food? How
。 这种食物里都有些什么？
when you ingest it will your body
摄入后身体会有什么
respond to it? Both from you know
反应？ 从
glucose levels which I'm sure many have
血糖水平（我相信很多人都听说过）
heard of to insulin responses to all
到胰岛素反应，所有这些
this different nuance. A lot of that
细微差别都值得关注。 这很大程度上取决于
comes down to nutrition but it also is
营养，但也与
things like exercise. Exercise such a
运动​​等因素有关。 运动
powerful impact on metabolism,
对新陈代谢有着强大的影响，这
incredibly important for overall health.
对整体健康至关重要。
But from a personal perspective, this
但从个人角度来看，这段
journey has been very honestly selfish
旅程对我来说其实非常自私
for me. I wanted to understand how to
。 我想了解如何才能
get the best performance, the best for
达到最佳状态，同时也要保证
health for myself. And I very quickly
自己的健康。 我很快
realized that uh you know some of the
意识到，一些
most powerful strategies out there were
最有效的策略
actually not necessarily the ones that
实际上并不一定是
were being told to me when I went to the
我去医生办公室时医生告诉我的那些策略，
doctor's office because I went through
因为在我
early on in my my journey with with
早期
trying to overcome some of these these
克服这些
challenges.
挑战的旅程中，我经历了一些非常戏剧性的时刻。
&gt;&gt; So take me back to the start of your
所以，请带我回到你
story in the earliest context that's
故事的最初阶段，回到最早的
relevant to understand
相关背景，以便了解
why you became the person you became. I
你为什么会成为现在的你。 我的
mean, I've got some photos here from
意思是，我这里有一些
your from your childhood which are
你小时候的照片，是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; very very telling. And you know, some of
非常非常说明问题。 你知道，
our listeners might be listening on
我们的一些听众可能只听
audio alone, so they might not be able
音频，所以他们可能无法
to see these these visuals on the
在屏幕上看到这些图像
screen.
。
&gt;&gt; So, if you could describe some of these
所以，如果你能
these pictures for me
为我描述一下这些图片的话
&gt;&gt; when Yeah.
。
Um
嗯，
it brings back some powerful memories of
这让我想起了
uh the challenges with obesity for me.
我与肥胖作斗争时的一些深刻记忆。
Um you know the the picture on the right
嗯，你知道右边这张照片
is just a picture with on a a family
是我们一家人
adventure um where we went to the we go
外出旅行时拍的，嗯，我们去了……
I go fishing with my dad a lot. You know
我经常和爸爸一起去钓鱼。 你知道
I'm very heavy at the time. I was, you
我那时体重很重。 你
know, uh, obese and, um, and the picture
知道，我以前很胖，而且，嗯，
on the right here, this really gets me
右边这张照片真的让我很受伤，
because, um, you know, I did, you did
因为，嗯，你知道，我，你，我做了
everything I was told, right? I
所有被告知要做的事情，对吧？ 我一直
exercised all the time. I ate what I I
坚持锻炼。 我吃我
was supposed to eat or what my doctor
应该吃的食物，或者医生
recommended, what the fitness magazines
建议的食物，以及健身杂志
recommended, but I was just constantly
建议的食物，但我却不断地面临
fat tissue. And I had no idea how
脂肪组织不断增加的挑战。 我当时完全不知道
damaging that actually was to my body.
这会对我的身体造成多大的伤害。
And, and I think the vast majority of
而且，我认为绝大多数
people also don't. Um, over 68% of
人也不这么认为。 嗯，目前美国超过68%的人口
America right now is obese. Okay, that
肥胖。 好的，这
means 7 out of 10 people walking around
意味着在美国街头行走的10个人中，有7个是
America have obesity. And we know that
肥胖者。 我们知道，
the second you start building more and
一旦你开始
more fat tissue on your body, insulin
在体内积累越来越多的脂肪组织，胰岛素
levels rise almost double immediately
水平就会立即翻倍，甚至在
before you even have symptoms of obesity
你出现肥胖症状
or uh tissue damage or organ damage or
、组织损伤、器官损伤或
anything along those lines. We know that
类似症状之前就会如此。 我们知道，
that almost immediately reduces insulin
这会几乎立即降低胰岛素
sensitivity. So how well insulin, this
敏感性。 那么，胰岛素这种
very powerful fat storage hormone, is
非常有效的脂肪储存激素，
able to actually bring nutrients from
究竟能将血液中的营养物质输送
the blood into tissues. That goes down
到组织中吗？ 这个数值会下降到
around 34 to 35% uh and early stages of
大约 34% 到 35%，也就是肥胖的早期阶段
obesity.
。   简单来说
me, insulin is basically the uber which
，胰岛素就像是汽车里的优步，它能把
takes things out of your blood and puts
血液里的物质输送到
them where they need to be.
需要的地方。
&gt;&gt; It's essentially like a thermostat for
它本质上就像血糖的恒温器
blood glucose. That's how most people
。 大多数人都是这么
know it. So as blood glucose levels
知道的。 因此，当血糖水平
rise, it works as a thermostat to let's
升高时，它就像恒温器一样，会
say release cool air to bring it back
释放冷空气来
down. In this case, releases insulin to
降低血糖水平。 在这种情况下，会释放胰岛素，
bring blood glucose back into range. As
使血糖恢复正常水平。 当
blood glucose drops, insulin is stopped.
血糖下降时，胰岛素停止分泌。
It stops releasing insulin out of these
它会阻止这些被
cells called the beta cells. And
称为β细胞的细胞释放胰岛素。
ultimately, what your body is trying to
最终，你的身体想要
do is keep the, you know, one teaspoon
做的就是保留
of sugar that's in your blood that is
血液中那至关重要的一茶匙糖分，这
critical for your life. If it goes up,
对你的生命至关重要。 如果温度升高，
it can cause damage. If it goes low, it
可能会造成损害。 如果血压过低，
can be life-threatening. in this very
可能会危及生命。 在这个非常非常
very tight range and it build it builds
小的范围内，它建立了
a number of mechanisms to ultimately
一系列机制，最终
make sure and ensure that you don't go
确保你不会
outside of that range. But imagine
超出这个范围。 但想象一下，如果
losing the one molecule that directly
失去了直接控制这一过程的分子会怎样？
&gt;&gt; You're wearing two devices I believe on
我相信你现在身上佩戴着两台设备
you at the moment. So you've got this
。 所以你已经掌握了这一点
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; What is the device on your arm?
你手臂上戴的是什么装置？
&gt;&gt; It's an insulin pump.
这是胰岛素泵。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; So Stephen, your body produces insulin.
斯蒂芬，你的身体会产生胰岛素。
Most people who are probably listening
大多数正在听
to this, they their body probably also
这段话的人，
produces insulin unless they have type 1
除非患有 1 型糖尿病，否则他们的身体可能也会产生胰岛素
diabetes. And so when my body no longer
。 所以，当我的身体
produces this molecule anymore, there's
不再产生这种分子时，就必须有
got to be a way to get it. It sits on my
办法获取它。 它 24 小时都戴在我的
arm 24/7 because it's a way of
手臂上，因为它
essentially packaging a pancreas that I
本质上是将我
don't have anymore and putting it on my
不再拥有的胰腺包装起来，放在我的
arm and and and a way of getting that
手臂上，从而获得
same type of of insulin.
相同类型的胰岛素。
&gt;&gt; And you have a CGM as well.
你也有一台动态血糖监测仪。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So on my stomach here, so on my
。 所以，我肚子上这里，我
stomach here is a CGM,
肚子上这里是一个 CGM，
&gt;&gt; which is a continuous glucose monitor.
也就是持续血糖监测仪。
&gt;&gt; CGM is a way of tracking sugar levels or
CGM（持续血糖监测）是一种追踪血糖或
glucose levels.
葡萄糖水平的方法。   这
&gt;&gt; And both of those devices link to your
两个设备都与
phone, which is in front of you. Um, and
你面前的手机相连。 嗯，
I'll throw that up on the screen so
我会把它放到屏幕上，这样
people can see,
大家就能看到，是的
&gt;&gt; yes,
，那大概是什么样子
&gt;&gt; what that what that kind of looks like.
。
&gt;&gt; So on this device, you have
在这个设备上，有
a green line that is glucose levels.
一条绿线，代表血糖水平。
Okay, my blood sugar says that it's 109
好的，我的血糖显示现在是109
right now. Which means that the
。 这意味着
signal of glucose is
葡萄糖的间质信号是
&gt;&gt; interstitial meaning within not in the
间质性的，也就是说它不是在
blood but in the tissues.
血液中，而是在组织中。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So the amount of glucose right
。 因此，
outside the blood around the tissues and
血液周围组织中的葡萄糖含量，
that signal is an indication of the
这个信号可以指示
amount of glucose in the blood. That's
血液中的葡萄糖含量。 那是
the green line. Okay, it says that I'm
绿线。 好的，它显示我
109 right now. So average blood sugar
现在109岁了。 因此，
levels using milligrams per deciliter is
以毫克/分升为单位的平均血糖水平为
70 to 120. That's considered normal.
70 至 120。这被认为是正常的。
Below that is blue lines almost like
下面有一些蓝色的线条，
looks like squares and triangles. Those
看起来很像正方形和三角形。 这些
are illustrations of insulin being
是胰岛素注射的示意图，
administered but they're not perfect
但它们并非完美无缺的
devices. Despite them being premier and
设备。 尽管它们是一流的，而且
you know the most advanced technology on
您也知道它们是市场上最先进的技术
the market, there are significant
，但它们也存在很大的
limitations to them. Um, I have actually
局限性。 嗯，我
watching earlier that said you think
之前看过你的一段视频，里面提到你认为
having high blood sugar over a long time
长期高血糖
is the biggest cause of long-term health
是导致长期健康问题的最大原因
problems.
。
&gt;&gt; When you're focused on improving your
当你专注于改善
overall health, you have to find out
整体健康状况时，你必须找出
what matters most, right? So, what
什么才是最重要的，对吗？ 那么，
what's the hierarchy uh uh in the
在健康领域，层级结构是怎样的呢？
health, you know, 1 2 3 4 5? What
比如说，1 2 3 4 5？ 其中
matters most on that? And we can look at
最重要的是什么？ 我们可以
that by looking at risk factors uh for
通过观察
future disease. Well, the number one
未来疾病的风险因素来了解这一点。
cause of death in the United States and
在美国乃至
across many parts of the world is
世界许多地区，
cardiovascular disease. Well, it's also
心血管疾病是导致死亡的首要原因。 它也是由于
with diabetes. And when you look at what
糖尿病导致的首要死亡原因。 当你查看哪些因素
are the strongest predictors of
最能预测
developing some form of cardiovascular
心血管
disease,
疾病的发生时，就会
a measure called HBA1C comes up at the
发现 HBA1C 指标名列前茅
top. HBA1C is a average measurement of
。  HBA1C 是
your blood glucose over a two to three
过去两到三个月内血糖的平均测量值
month period of time. And that is
。 而这
incredibly powerful at predicting future
对于预测未来
risk for let's say diseases of the eye,
患眼疾、
diseases of the kidney or even
肾病甚至
cardiovascular disease. And so when I
心血管疾病的风险来说，是非常有效的。 所以，当我
think about how do we tackle uh
思考我们如何
improving health or in in particularly
改善健康，特别是如何应对
in these these common much more common
这些常见的
diseases,
疾病时，
glucose control sits at the very top of
血糖控制就处于
that pyramid. And if unregulated, it's
这个金字塔的顶端。 如果不加以监管，这就
equivalent to analogy I often use, which
好比我经常用的比喻：
is you're you're driving a car and
你开着一辆车，
you're focused on what type of rims you
却只关注你的轮毂是什么型号
have, but you don't even have an engine
，但你的车里甚至连发动机都没有
in the car. Like your engine doesn't
。 就像你的引擎坏了
work, or you don't have an a chassis or
，或者你没有底盘或
an axis, but yet you're you're focused
轴，但你却专注
on rims or a sound system. And so the
于轮毂或音响系统。 因此，对于
diseases like diabetes, that matters
糖尿病等疾病而言，最重要的因素
most is HBA1C.
是糖化血红蛋白 (HbA1C)。
&gt;&gt; So does that just mean that we should be
所以这是否意味着我们应该
eating less sugar?
少吃糖？
So if we wanted to control the most
因此，如果我们想要控制
powerful risk factor in diabetes,
糖尿病中最强大的风险因素，
we would need to understand how to
我们就需要了解如何
regulate it. Right? So then let's look
调节它。 正确的？ 那么，让我们从
at the science of this. Well, the
科学的角度来探讨一下这个问题。
science says that carbohydrates,
科学研究表明，碳水化合物是
regulating elevations in glucose at
调节一天中
every single meal of the day. Well, most
每一餐血糖升高的最有效因素。 嗯，大多数
people are eating three to four plus
人每天都要吃三到四
meals every single day. And so the very
顿饭。 因此，
first logical thing to look at is food
首先要考虑的合乎逻辑的事情就是食物，
because what you're consuming has the
因为你所摄入的食物
most potent impact on glucose control
对血糖控制的影响最大，
and glucose control has the most potent
而血糖控制
impact on your health not only today but
对你的健康不仅现在，而且
in the future. And so focusing on on
将来都会产生最大的影响。 因此，关注
nutrition makes sense. But this isn't
营养是合理的。 但这并非
like a new phenomenon. We've known that
一种新现象。 我们早就知道，
nutrition could be potentially
营养
life-saving for people. There's a a you
对人们的生命可能起到救命的作用。 你
know there's something called a
知道，有一种叫做
ketogenic diet if someone's heard this
生酮饮食的饮食方式，如果有人
before. It's a diet that dramatically
以前听说过的话。 这种饮食方式会大幅
reduces the amount of carbohydrates in
减少食物中的碳水化合物含量
the food. And the dramatic reduction in
。
carbohydrates in the food was used to
食物中碳水化合物的大幅减少被用来
save lives of patients with type 1 and
拯救 1 型和
type 2 diabetes since there was the
2 型糖尿病患者的生命，据
first report ever known to my knowledge
我所知，最早的报告
is in 19 or 1796 by a gentleman named a
是在 1796 年，由一位名叫约翰·
physician called John Row. He published
罗的医生撰写的。 他发表了
a report on two cases of diabetes
一篇关于两例糖尿病性贫血病例的报告，
malitis using basically a carbohydrate
主要通过
replete or reduced diet to resolve the
增加或减少碳水化合物的饮食来治愈该
disease. But we know that some of the
疾病。 但我们知道，一些
most premier diabetists meaning people
最顶尖的糖尿病专家（即
who study diabetes or treat people with
研究糖尿病或治疗
diabetes were utilizing these strategies
糖尿病患者的人）早在一百多年前就开始使用这些策略，直到
discovered in 1921 that this diet could
1921 年我们才发现这种饮食
also help neurological disorders like
还可以帮助治疗癫痫等神经系统疾病
seizures and beyond. And so the the
等等。 因此，
phenomenon of nutrition playing a role
营养在整体健康中发挥作用的现象
in overall health is is certainly not
当然不是什么
new. It's actually only recently that
新鲜事。 事实上，直到最近
we're rediscovering century old wisdom
我们才重新发现
of what nutrition can do for overall
营养对整体
health uh due to the emergence of an
健康的重要性这一百年智慧，这主要归功于
explosion in science that has really
科学的飞速发展，它真正
drove a ton of public interest into this
激发了公众对这种
kind of unique dietary strategy.
独特饮食策略的浓厚兴趣。
&gt;&gt; So the ketogenic diet then um it's a
所以，生酮饮食，嗯，
diet that I'm familiar with because it's
我比较熟悉这种饮食方式，因为
a diet that I cycle in and out of
我一年到头都会时不时地采用这种饮食方式
throughout the year. probably I'm in a
。 我可能
ketogenic state three or four times a
一年有三四次处于生酮状态，
year and I use the little keto reader
我用这个小小的酮体检测仪
just to check my blood ketone levels.
只是为了检查我的血液酮体水平。   对于
unfamiliar with the ke ketogenic diet? I
不熟悉生酮饮食的人来说，什么是生酮饮食？ 我算是它的
I'm a bit of an advocate for it. So I'm
支持者。 所以我对它
fairly familiar but I that's also taught
相当熟悉，但这同时也让
me how unfamiliar people are with it
我意识到人们对它有多么不熟悉，
because I talk to my friends about it
因为我和朋友们谈论它时，发现有
and there's a lot of misconceptions.
很多误解。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; If you're on a ketogenic diet, what are
如果你正在进行生酮饮食，
you eating?
你都在吃什么？
&gt;&gt; So typically what when someone
所以，当人们
visualizes a ketogenic diet, I think
想到生酮饮食时，我认为有
there's a lot of misinformation. and
很多误解。
they think it's just steak and bacon.
他们以为这只是牛排和培根。
Um, and I guess for some people it might
嗯，我想对某些人来说可能
be that, but it's actually uh if we're
是这样，但实际上，如果我们
talking about a well- formulated
谈论的是一个精心设计的
ketogenic diet, we're talking about
生酮饮食，我们谈论的是
green leafy vegetables, things that we
绿叶蔬菜，也就是我们
typically associate with health. You
通常与健康联系在一起的东西。 你
know, salads, uh, broccoli, asparagus,
知道，沙拉，呃，西兰花，芦笋，
cauliflower, these kind of uh,
花椰菜，这些
nutrient-dense green leafy vegetables
营养丰富的绿叶蔬菜，
that are high in fiber and
富含纤维和
phytonutrients.
植物营养素。
Then you also have protein as a
此外，蛋白质也是
component of that. that can come from
其中的组成部分。 这可能来自
meat that can come from fish in the form
肉类，也可能来自鱼类（例如
of salmon, eggs, uh cheeses, a little
鲑鱼）、鸡蛋、奶酪，还有一些
like nuts. And then you also have the
坚果之类的东西。 此外，
rest of the diet which is made up of
饮食中还包含其他
fat. And this can come a lot of times
脂肪。 而且这种情况很多时候可能
from um various plant forms. This can
来自各种植物形态。
come, you know, from like olive oil,
你知道，这可能来自橄榄油、
avocado oil.
鳄梨油之类的东西。   那
&gt;&gt; And what are you removing then?
你要移除的是什么？
&gt;&gt; Sugary starchy carbohydrates. So you're
含糖淀粉类碳水化合物。 所以你
you're you know you're not having
知道，你不能吃
bagels, you're not having donuts, um
百吉饼，不能吃甜甜圈，也不能吃
white rice, pastas, these type of foods.
白米饭、意大利面之类的食物。   这些
diet is because these foods rapidly
食物之所以不属于这种饮食方案，是因为它们会迅速
elevate blood sugar levels. And the
升高血糖水平。
rapid elevation in blood sugar also
血糖的快速升高也会导致
spikes insulin. Insulin shuts down fat
胰岛素水平飙升。 胰岛素会抑制脂肪
breakdown and the ability to take that
分解，并阻止
fat to the liver. The liver built this
脂肪被输送到肝脏。 肝脏构建了这种
amazing mechanism to be able to convert
神奇的机制，能够将
fat to ketone bodies because ketone
脂肪转化为酮体，因为
bodies fat can't actually longchain
酮体中的脂肪实际上不能穿过血脑屏障。长链
fatty acids which is the primary form of
脂肪酸是
fat that you consume in the food you eat
你在食物中摄入的主要脂肪形式，
and also the type that's broken down
也是
from your own fat tissue can't readily
你自身脂肪组织分解产生的脂肪类型
cross the bloodb brain barrier. And we
。 我们
know that glucose is a fuel for the
知道葡萄糖是
brain. But what happens if you fast or
大脑的燃料。 但是，如果你禁食或
you don't consume a lot of carbohydrates
不摄入大量碳水化合物，导致
and you have low insulin levels and you
胰岛素水平低下，而
can't con transport the fat which is now
无法运输脂肪（脂肪现在是
your primary fuel source on a ketogenic
你在生酮饮食中的主要燃料来源），会发生什么情况呢？
diet because you reduce glucose or
因为你减少了
carbohydrates in the diet which causes a
饮食中的葡萄糖或碳水化合物，导致
reduction in glucose. The reduction in
血糖降低。
glucose lowers insulin. The reduction in
血糖降低会降低胰岛素水平。
insulin causes fat to be rapidly broken
胰岛素水平降低会导致脂肪迅速
down and now becomes your primary fuel
分解，脂肪随即成为你的主要能量
source.
来源。
&gt;&gt; And so there's an evolutionary basis for
所以这背后是有进化论基础的
this, right? Because once upon a time we
，对吧？ 因为在过去，我们
might have gone long periods of time
可能很长时间都
without eating something. And so our
没有吃过东西。 因此，我们的
body turns inwards and starts using our
身体开始向内消耗，利用
fat stores as a mechanism to to to fuel
脂肪储备作为能量来源，
our body and that's why it produces
这就是它产生
ketones. Basically the evolution of this
酮体的原因。 基本上，这种
diet was believed to be a cyclical
饮食方式的演变被认为是
meaning on and off pattern in human
人类历史上一个循环往复的模式，
history because if we were to go through
因为如果我们经历
bouts of abundance in food, we probably
食物充足的时期，我们可能会
consume it as much as we can in one
在某一
moment and then we're seeking the next
时刻尽可能多地消耗掉食物，然后我们就会寻找下一
meal and seeking the next meal. What
顿饭，再寻找下一顿饭。
happens in that in between time? If
在那段中间时期会发生什么？ 如果
you're 100% reliant on having food 24/7
你像我们目前的食物环境一样，100% 依赖 24/7 全天候的食物供应
environment, you would never survive
，那么从进化角度来看，你永远无法生存
beyond a few days.
超过几天。   我们
With the ability to switch from a
能够从以
carbohydrate-based metabolism over to a
碳水化合物为基础的代谢切换到以
fat-based metabolism, we store months
脂肪为基础的代谢，这样，即使没有营养，我们也能储存数月
and months and months of fat energy in
甚至数月的脂肪能量
the event that we don't have nutrient.
。
So it's a one of the most powerful
所以，这是
survival mechanisms we have to survive
我们在饥荒时期生存下来的最强大的生存机制之一
uh moments of famine. But we also have
。 但自圣经时代以来，我们也知道
that fasting has therapeutic potential.
禁食具有治疗潜力。
You know most potently in and the
你知道，它最有效的
ability to what would be described as
作用是能够
attenuate seizures. You know convulsion
减轻癫痫发作。 你知道，
like behavior was described when you
当
just completely eliminate food. actually
完全不进食时，会出现类似抽搐的行为。 事实上，这
a common strategy in many religious
在许多宗教习俗中是一种常见的策略，
practices because of its quote unquote
因为它具有所谓的“
healing properties. Well, now we
疗愈”功效。 现在我们
actually know that fasting induces a
知道，禁食会诱发
state of ketosis and we know that
酮症状态，而且我们知道，
ketosis is actually shown to in many of
在很多情况下，酮症实际上对
seizure like seizures. We've known since
癫痫等疾病具有治疗作用。 早在
the 1920 one out of the Mayo Clinic that
1920 年梅奥诊所的研究中，我们就知道
ketogenic diets not only mimic the
生酮饮食不仅可以模拟
physiology of fasting but also attenuate
禁食的生理过程，还可以减轻
the seizures in children with epilepsy.
癫痫儿童的癫痫发作。
And that work has subsequently gone on
随后，
to John Hopkins and other research
约翰·霍普金斯大学和其他研究
institutes to show that this is a very
机构也开展了相关研究，结果表明，这不仅是一种治疗
verified strategy for not just epilepsy
癫痫的有效策略，
but it has been used for obesity, type 1
而且几个世纪以来一直被用于治疗肥胖症、1 型
diabetes, type two diabetes for for
糖尿病和 2 型糖尿病
centuries at this point. Um, and it all
。 嗯，这一切都
starts with the reduction of
始于减少
carbohydrates in the diet.
饮食中的碳水化合物。
beneficial to me, but also I know Joe
对我来说最有益的事情之一，而且我知道乔·
Rogan has talked about this before is as
罗根以前也谈到过这一点，就是作为一个花
a sort of a podcaster that spends a lot
很多
of time talking, you notice high
时间说话的播客主持人，你会注意到
variance in your ability to think,
你的思考能力和
&gt;&gt; for long periods of time based on my
长时间表达能力会根据我的
blood ketone levels and my
血液酮体水平和我的
&gt;&gt; my sort my diet broadly um but
饮食（大致来说，但
specifically the amount of ketones that
具体来说是
are in my blood.
血液中的酮体含量）而出现很大的波动。   这
Why is that? Why is it that I feel like
是为什么？ 为什么我觉得
thinking when I'm on the ketogenic diet
在生酮饮食
or taking exogenous ketones versus when
或服用外源性酮体时，我的沟通和思考效率比在
I'm having a normal western high higher
正常的西式高
carb diet? A lot of people
碳水化合物饮食时更高？
would know why this is if they had the
如果人们拥有与 1 型糖尿病患者相同的工具和洞察力，他们就会明白其中的原因
diabetes gives. Because when you're
。 因为当你
consuming that diet, what is often
食用这种饮食时，经常会
happening is near constant elevations
发生
lows in blood sugar levels that we know
血糖水平的持续波动，我们知道这是由于
are ascribed to changes in energy
能量水平的变化引起的
levels. So, we know that high blood
。 所以，我们知道高
sugar levels, someone can Google if
血糖水平，如果有人感兴趣，可以上网
they're they're so interested to look up
搜索“
the term high blood sugar hyperlycemia
高血糖症”
or low blood sugar or hypoglycemia and
或“低血糖症”，然后
just type in symptoms and you'll see a
输入症状，你会看到
laundry list of things like fatigue,
一长串症状，如疲劳、易怒、注意力
irritability, lack of concentration, uh
不集中、
shakiness. These are all symptoms of a
颤抖等等。 这些症状与
lot of what you're describing, right?
你描述的很多症状都吻合，对吧？
Which is change in your your your
这会影响你的注意力
ability to concentrate, your energy
集中能力和精力
levels. It's a very very clear that
水平。 很明显，
glucose levels are linked to that. We
血糖水平与此有关。 我们
also know that the chain
也知道这条链子
&gt;&gt; ju just to be clear. So is that when I'm
只是说清楚而已。 所以，那是在我
at the high or the low in the glucose?
血糖高的时候还是低的时候？
So if I you know if you if you ate one
所以，如果你现在吃了一个这样的橙子，你知道
&gt;&gt; what are these oranges? Tangerines.
这些橙子是什么吗？ 橘子。
&gt;&gt; Oranges. Yep.
橙子。 是的。
&gt;&gt; Um if you ate one of these right now,
嗯，如果你现在吃了这些东西，
your blood glucose levels are going to
你的血糖水平
go up presumably.
大概会升高。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. Because these oranges are composed
。 因为这些橙子是由
of bound sugar molecules together. So
结合在一起的糖分子构成的。 所以
most fruit has a structural component to
大多数水果都有结构成分，这就是
it which is why you see an it it has
为什么你会看到它有体积，
like a has is has mass to it right it's
有重量，对吧？它
not just a liquid and then that
不仅仅是液体。然后，这种
structural component binds together as a
结构成分会结合在一起，形成糖类，
they call them polysaccharides and those
这些糖类被称为多糖。
polysaccharides when you consume them
当你食用这些多糖时，
your gut actually takes those breaks
你的肠道会将它们分解
them down into individual glucose
成单个的葡萄糖
molecules
分子，然后
to then be absorbed into the bloodstream
被吸收到血液中。这时
that's when the insulin is released,
胰岛素就会释放，
that's when the insulin takes that
胰岛素会将这些
glucose and stores it into tissues like
葡萄糖储存到
the muscle and the liver uh for future
肌肉和肝脏等组织中，以备将来
glucose needs. Uh and so yes, we would
需要葡萄糖时使用。 嗯，所以，是的，我们会
presume that with this high or oranges
认为，在这种高血糖的情况下，橙子
or even most fruits, pastas, rices would
甚至大多数水果、意大利面、米饭都会
all elevate blood sugar levels, but then
升高血糖水平，但这也会
that accompanies with a high insulin
伴随高胰岛素
load, right? So the more of the oranges,
负荷，对吧？ 所以，橙子吃得越多，
the more insulin that you would need.
需要的胰岛素就越多。
And you know, despite many of these
你知道，尽管这些
foods being considered very healthy,
食物中的许多都被认为是非常健康的，但
those with
患有
metabolic disease or metabolic
代谢疾病或代谢功能
dysfunction may not may have a be more
障碍的人可能更
vulnerable to even what would typically
容易受到通常
be considered healthy foods. Um, and
被认为是健康食物的影响。 嗯，
type 1 diabetes is a is a powerful
1 型糖尿病就是一个强有力的
example of that.
例子。
&gt;&gt; So, you said you'd you'd open to eating
所以，你说过你会愿意尝试吃
one of these. We've got your blood
其中一个。 我们已经测出了您的
glucose and insulin levels, which we're
血糖和胰岛素水平，我们
going to put on screen for people that
会把这些数据显示在屏幕上，供
are watching. And it'll be interesting
观看的人查看。
to see how quickly we see that orange,
橙子被许多人
which is considered a health food by
视为健康食品
many people, have an impact on your
，我们很想知道它对
glucose and insulin levels.
血糖和胰岛素水平的影响会有多快显现出来。   是的
&gt;&gt; So, yeah. So, so what I'm I'm going to
。 所以，我接下来
do is normally I would I would never do
要做的事，通常我绝不会这样做
this, but I I think it's very important
，但我认为这
for people to understand,
对人们来说非常重要，
especially those at home who either have
尤其是那些患有
a chronic disease, which is most
慢性疾病的人（目前大多数
Americans at this point, or kids who
美国人都是如此），或者
have a disease like diabetes, what the
患有糖尿病等疾病的孩子，让他们了解这
impact really could be. So let's say
究竟会造成什么影响。 假设
oranges are considered a superfood uh by
橙子被
the American Diabetes Association. So
美国糖尿病协会认定为超级食物。 因此，
almost every organization USDA f or USDA
几乎所有组织都强烈推荐这种水果，例如美国农业部、
American Diabetes Association and beyond
美国糖尿病协会等等，推荐
the amount of or is three oranges.
量为三个橙子。
Three oranges is probably going to make
三个橙子大概含有
up around h 70 to 90 grams of
70到90克
carbohydrates. For me, my energy needs
碳水化合物。 对我来说，我每天的能量需求大约是
calories per day. Now, the activity I'm
卡路里。 现在，根据我
consuming,
目前的活动量，
if I were to
如果我要
eat the amount of carbohydrates
摄入每日推荐的碳水化合物量（
by, let's say, the USDA guidelines, that
比如，根据美国农业部指南，大约是 55%），那么
than this at le if I split up all my
如果我把所有
calories over four meals. And so,
卡路里分成四餐，我至少需要摄入这个量或更多。 因此，
This is
这是
an opportunity to see what this will
一个机会，可以看看
type 1 diabetes if you consume will be a
如果你摄入的
amount of carbohydrates that I would
碳水化合物量大约相当于
consume per day if I was on a standard
我按照标准饮食每天摄入量的五分之一，那么它对血糖水平和 1 型糖尿病的实际影响是什么
diet.
。
&gt;&gt; The the ketogenic diet they typically
他们通常
say that to stay within it you need to
说，要坚持生酮饮食，你需要
carbohydrates a day? And it's roughly
每天摄入的碳水化合物低于大约 50 克？ 之所以说
because 50 grams of carbohydrates per
每天 50 克碳水化合物
day is a
是一个
rough number that we suspect most people
大致的数字，是因为我们认为大多数人
will be able to get carbohydrates low
都能将碳水化合物摄入量降低
enough to where insulin would be
到胰岛素水平
sufficiently low to produce ketone
足够低的程度，从而产生
bodies.
酮体。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; So there's variance depending on your
所以这取决于你的
insulin sensitivity and insulin response
胰岛素敏感性和胰岛素反应，
and I guess body weight as well is going
我想体重也是
to be a factor. big factor, major factor
一个因素。 这是一个重要因素，一个关键因素，
because anytime you're talking about
因为任何时候当你谈论
things like uh glucose, insulin is
葡萄糖、胰岛素之类的东西时，每个人的
always very individualized responses to
反应都是非常个性化的
each individual person.
。
&gt;&gt; I don't really I don't I try and stay
我不太喜欢吃
away from fruit these days. I don't
水果，最近尽量避免吃。 我不
know. I I berries and raspberries and
知道。 我喜欢浆果、覆盆子之类的东西，
stuff like that and cuz people tell me
因为有人告诉我它们
there's like polyphenols and black
含有多酚，还有
blackberries,
黑莓，
&gt;&gt; but those are totally uh co cohesive
但这些都
with the ketogenic diet
与生酮饮食完全契合，
&gt;&gt; because they're higher in fiber. So like
因为它们的纤维含量更高。 所以
you know half of where you're consuming,
你知道你摄入的食物中有一半（
not half, but a large portion of it
不是一半，而是很大一部分）是
fiber. So it's more about the net
纤维。 所以关键在于净
carbohydrates. It's the the glycemic
碳水化合物含量。 这是
metabolic impact of the food. So
食物对血糖代谢的影响。
&gt;&gt; if the fiber is non-digestible, which in
如果纤维是不可消化的（
fruit it isn't, then it shouldn't it
水果中的纤维是可以消化的），那么它就不应该被
doesn't count, right? So higher fiber
计入，对吗？ 因此，纤维
content. Most of the vegetables on a
含量更高。
ketogenic diet are higher fiber, you
生酮饮食中的大多数蔬菜都富含纤维，你
know,
知道，
&gt;&gt; because you know it's the it's the total
因为你知道，关键在于总
carbohydrate to fiber ratio. So the net
碳水化合物与纤维的比例。 所以
carbohydrates that really matter because
真正重要的是净碳水化合物，因为
that's the amount of that's the
那是
metabolic real metabolic impact of food.
食物对代谢的真正影响。   是的
Yeah. A lot of a lot of keto friendly
。 很多标榜适合生酮饮食的
foods say like net carbs or one gram or
食品都说净碳水化合物含量是1克之
something, but you look at it and you go
类的，但你一看，就会发现上面
[__] it says 20.
写着20克。
&gt;&gt; It's total [__] man. Is it?
这完全是胡扯。 是吗？
&gt;&gt; So, oh, 100%. Um, so I I've tested two
所以，哦，100%。 嗯，我测试了两种标签
on the label. Same as calories, same as
上标明适合生酮饮食的食品。 和卡路里一样，和
like fat, protein, even fiber. Um, and
脂肪、蛋白质甚至纤维一样。 嗯，
they can produce completely different
它们可能会产生完全不同的
responses. I mean, the food environment
反应。 我的意思是，如今的食品环境
nowadays, you essentially need almost a
，你基本上需要
PhD in nutrition or biochemistry to walk
营养学或生物化学博士学位才​​能
into a grocery store and be able to
走进一家杂货店，并且能够
understand what the hell's on the label.
看懂标签上到底是什么。
It's it is and I I don't want to sit
就是这样，我不想坐在
here and say like, oh, they they don't
这里说，哦，他们不
know. Like, no, they they know. I mean,
知道。 不，他们知道。 我的意思是，
there's are companies who have tons of
有些公司拥有大量的
resources, food scientists galore, and
资源，食品科学家也很多，
they're putting zero sugar on the label
他们把“零糖”
and keto friendly a as a trick because
和“生酮友好”之类的字眼当作噱头，因为
it's associated with health benefits,
这与健康益处有关，
right? There's all these studies on
对吧？ 有很多关于生
ketogenic diets that can they can show
酮饮食的研究表明，生酮饮食可以
to improve health. And so they want to
改善健康。 所以他们想把这个元素印
have that on their label. But what is
在自己的标签上。 但
often happening if you look on the back
如果你查看
of the label, there's about a hundred
标签背面，你会发现通常有大约一百种
different ingredients they can swap
不同的成分可以代替
sugar for for something that has the
糖，这些成分
same exact metabolic effect as sugar. So
与糖具有相同的代谢效果。 所以，
malitol, maltodextrin,
麦芽糖醇、麦芽糊精，
um all these different ingredients that
所有这些会
are going to cause glucose to go up
导致葡萄糖
rapidly, they'll just swap it and now
迅速升高的成分，他们都会用它们来代替，这样
you can put on your label zero sugar.
你就可以在标签上写上“零糖”了。
Have you been in a ketogenic diet since
自从确诊糖尿病以来，你一直都在进行生酮饮食吗
you were diagnosed with diabetes? Have
？
you cycled in and out of it yourself?
你本人是否也曾多次参与其中？
And if so, what have you noticed in
如果是这样，你注意到在进行
terms of when you are in that diet and
这种饮食和
when you're not? So, I actually came
不进行这种饮食时，身体有什么不同吗？ 实际上，我是在
across this diet a little over a decade
十多年前偶然接触到这种饮食方法的
ago. What I found is that almost every
。 我发现，在
blood meter that I was taking, this is
我使用过的几乎所有血糖仪中（这是在
before CGMs were present, I had to just
CGM 出现之前），我都需要
times a day to see what my blood sugars
每天扎针取血 6 到 10 次，才能知道我的血糖
were. I was finding that I was very
是多少。 我发现自己
rarely outside of the normal range. And
很少超出正常范围。 而且
I was also finding that I wasn't feeling
我发现，
when I transitioned to a ketogenic diet
当我几乎立即过渡到生酮饮食后，我的情绪不再出现剧烈的波动
almost immediately. My insulin
。 我的胰岛素
requirements dropped substantially uh
需求量大幅下降了
around 40 a little over 40%. So the uh
大约 40%，略高于 40%。 所以，
the amount of insulin I needed to take
我需要注射的胰岛素量
dropped dramatically, but I didn't have
大幅下降，但我没有
continuous glucose monitor. I didn't
持续血糖监测仪。 我无法
have this instant feedback of like what
立即获得诸如“
is my blood sugar doing? I just know I
我的血糖水平如何？”之类的反馈。 我只知道我
needed a heck of a lot less insulin. And
需要的胰岛素剂量大大减少了。
so what happened was I went into my
于是，我去了
doctor's office at the time. He happened
当时我的医生的办公室。 他当时恰好
to be the American Diabetes Association
是美国糖尿病协会
president at the time. He's like, "I've
主席。 他说：“我
diabetes before." He said, "What are you
以前从未见过 1 型糖尿病患者的血糖水平在正常范围内。” 他说：“你在
doing?" From that point forward, that's
做什么？” 从那时起，
when for me it like transitions even
对我来说，这就像是开启了
into like a lifelong journey of like,
一段终身的旅程。
"Wow, you know, obviously nutrition had
“哇，你知道，营养在我肥胖
a huge impact on me losing weight when I
时对我的减肥起到了巨大的作用
had obesity. Now it was directly
。现在，它直接
regulating this very powerful disease
调节着这种非常强大的疾病。
where upon diagnosis nearly all patients
几乎所有患者在确诊后，余生都将
are going to have high invariable
面临高
glucose levels for the rest of their
血糖且不稳定的局面
life. 99% of patients will never see
。99%的患者终生都无法恢复
normal metabolic control again for their
正常的代谢控制
life. 100% of them are expected to get
。100%的患者预计会出现
insulin resistance. And within 3 years
胰岛素抵抗。而且，在确诊的儿童中，我们会在3年内
we see neuroanatomical changes within
观察到大脑的神经解剖结构变化
the brain of children who are diagnosed.
。
What does that mean?
这意味着什么呢？这
&gt;&gt; So it means that when we look at MRI
意味着，当我们观察
scans of the brain, we see that children
大脑的核磁共振扫描时，我们会发现，患有1型糖尿病且
with high and variable glucose levels
血糖水平高且波动大的儿童，其大脑中
brain that are associated with normal
与正常
brain development and childhood, they're
大脑发育和儿童时期相关的白质和灰质类型发生了变化
not developing the same way. We and we
。我们
see this within 3 years and it's
在3年内就能观察到这种变化，而且它与
directly linked to the poor glucose
血糖控制不佳直接相关
control. We also know that we see signs
。我们也知道，我们会观察到
of the early signals of aththeroscerotic
早期信号……
progression in children within four
儿童四年内动脉粥样硬化进展
years.
。动脉
&gt;&gt; Atheroscerotic progression, what's that?
粥样硬化进展是什么？
cardiovascular disease. And how do we
心血管疾病是全球主要的死亡原因之一。那么，它是如何
get that? Well,
发生的呢？
you have changes in your blood vessel
血管
and how it functions is the first and
及其功能的变化是未来血管内斑块或阻塞的最初也是
earliest signal of future what will
最早的信号，
ultimately cause things like heart
最终会导致心脏病
attacks or strokes. Well, in type 1
发作或中风等疾病。在1型
diabetes, we see that children who have
糖尿病中，我们发现
high invariable glucose levels, again,
血糖水平持续偏高的儿童，
99% of patients are expected to just
99%的患者预计终生都会
live this way for the rest of their
保持这种状态
life. If they follow standard of care,
。如果他们接受标准治疗，
if they follow the doctor's orders,
遵医嘱，
their blood vessels literally
他们的血管
functionally and structurally change.
功能和结构就会发生变化。
Their blood vessels will now shift from
他们的血管会从
being this very compliant uh almost like
非常顺应，几乎像
a a smooth wave to that blood vessel now
光滑的波浪一样，
becomes very rigid. It starts to build
变得非常僵硬。血管周围开始积累
collagen at more and more collagen
胶原蛋白，胶原蛋白越来越多，血管
around it becomes stiffer and stiffer.
变得越来越硬。
It's almost like taking a hose and
这就像打开一根软管，
turning on a hose and pinching the hose.
然后捏住软管的…… 就像软管一样。
When you pinch the hose, as you become
当你捏住软管时，随着软管
stiffer and as you shrink the size of
变硬，
the blood vessel, it goes faster. And so
血管壁变窄，血液流动速度就会加快。因此，
we can measure that by the speed of the
我们可以通过
blood in the body. Another clear signal
血液在体内的流速来测量这一点。这是另一个清晰且强有力的信号，
that the blood vessel is starting to
表明血管在
change before you see plaque, before you
出现斑块或
see blockages, I mean decades prior.
阻塞之前，甚至在几十年前就开始发生变化。
These are all happening in childhood by
顺便说一句，这些变化都发生在儿童时期
the way. You know, 10 to, you know, 10
。你知道，在10
to 14 year olds diagnosed with type 1
到14岁的孩子中，如果被诊断出患有1型
diabetes. we see that the blood vessel
糖尿病，我们发现他们的血管
isn't able to respond to what they call
无法对所谓的“
sheer stress Stephen. So that means
剪切应力”做出反应。这意味着，
let's say you go for a run uh this
假设你今天
morning Stephen and your blood pressure
早上跑步，你的血压
initially increases because as your
最初会升高，因为随着
heart rate increases the speed of the
心率加快，
blood increases the amount of pressure
血液流速加快，
on the vascular wall increases that a
血管壁上的压力也随之增加。
phenomenon when the blood moves fast
当血液快速流
through blood vessels it it causes
过血管时，会对
stress against the blood vessels. That's
血管造成压力。但这
not a bad thing. It's actually a signal
并非坏事。它实际上是
for the blood vessel to release
血管释放一
something called nitric oxide. Nitric
氧化氮的信号。一
oxide is a potent called vaso diilator.
氧化氮是一种强效的血管舒张剂。 血管扩张剂。
It causes the blood vessels to open up
它能使血管扩张
and this is how your body responds
，这是身体
normally to stress. Okay, you go for an
对压力的正常反应。比如，
exercise vasoddilation or vaso
运动时血管扩张，运动后血管
constriction then vaso dilation um or
收缩，然后血​​管再次扩张，
you know and these are normal responses
这些都是身体的正常反应
the body has. Well, what happens in type
。然而，
1 diabetes very early on is that the
1型糖尿病早期就会出现一
ability to produce nitric oxide is
氧化氮生成能力
diminished. You're not able to respond
下降的情况。你无法应对
to high stress load. So, not only are
高强度的压力负荷。因此，不仅
the blood vessels becoming stiffer, but
血管会变得僵硬，而且
now the blood vessels aren't able to
血管
even respond as well to the stress. And
对压力的反应能力也会下降。
so, as you're looking at this and you're
随着
looking over time, you see these early
时间的推移，你会看到这些早期
signals of athoscorotic progression.
信号，即动脉粥样硬化进展的迹象。
also see very early on that it was once
此外，人们一度
expected that all patients with type 1
认为所有1型
diabetes would have eye damage some form
糖尿病患者都会出现某种形式的
of eye damage called retinopathy where
眼损伤，称为视网膜病变，会导致
you start to lose vision eventually can
视力逐渐丧失，最终可能在
go blind within 20 years of diagnosis.
确诊后20年内失明。
So most people are diagnosed in 10 to 14
大多数患者在10到14
years of age which means by 30 to 34
岁之间确诊，这意味着到30到34
years of age you're going to see a lot
岁时，你就会看到……
of patients who have altered eye
很多患者会出现眼
function andor some who are blind. Now
功能改变，甚至失明。虽然这种情况
that has extended out over time, but we
已经持续了一段时间，但我们
know that all patients with this disease
知道，所有患有这种疾病（
because of high and variable glucose
由于血糖水平高且波动较大）的患者，
complication in their lifetime if they
如果
follow standard of care advice today.
遵循目前的标准治疗建议，一生中至少会出现一种并发症。
Even with the best technologies out
即使拥有最先进的技术
there, there is no pharmaceutical
，目前也没有任何药物可以
intervention. There is no technology
干预，也没有任何技术可以使
that normalizes this disease. And the
这种疾病正常化。
effects of these high invariable glucose
高血糖
levels and insulin resistance that
水平及其伴随的胰岛素抵抗的影响
is cumulative
是累积性的，呈
dose dependent and not completely
剂量依赖性，而且无法完全
reversible. Which means that once you're
逆转。这意味着一旦
diagnosed, the clock starts ticking. It
确诊，时间就开始倒计时。这就像
just like smoking. The more you do, the
吸烟一样，吸烟越多，吸烟
earlier you do it, the earlier the
越早，
impact and the more lost life you
影响就越早显现，寿命也
probably will get. And there was a study
可能越短。一项
done with 326 participants that found
针对326名参与者的研究发现，
that the keto diet can increase glycemic
生酮饮食可以改善
control of patients with diabetes. That
糖尿病患者的血糖控制。这项研究发表
was in the precision nutrition
在《精准营养》
publication. When it says it can
杂志上。它所说的“
increase glycemic control, what does
改善血糖控制”是什么
that mean?
意思呢？这就是
&gt;&gt; So is that what we were talking about
我们刚才讨论的内容吗？是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. So if you when you do a diet known
。所以，如果你采用一种叫做
as a ketogenic diet, you're reducing
生酮饮食的饮食方式， 你在减少
carbohydrates. Well, when carbohydrates
碳水化合物的摄入。嗯，
are consumed, they elevate glucose
摄入碳水化合物会升高血糖
levels. Well, if you dramatically reduce
水平。如果你大幅减少
the amount of carbohydrates consumed,
碳水化合物的摄入量，就
you're not having those same type of
不会出现同样的
glucose elevations and fluctuations
血糖升高和波动，
because you're not consuming the most
因为你不再摄入生活
potent glucose elevating factor in our
中最强效的血糖升高因素——
life, which is carbohydrates. And so
碳水化合物。所以，
when they talk about improvements in
当人们谈到
glycemic control, it is the measure of
血糖控制的改善时，指的是
24-hour over multiple day levels of
24小时内血液
glucose in the circulation. And how well
循环中葡萄糖水平的平均值，以及血糖水平
is that being controlled within a normal
在正常健康范围内的控制情况。
&gt;&gt; And so is your goal then to
那么，你的目标是
encourage people to restrict
鼓励人们限制
&gt;&gt; in their diet? But you know because
饮食中的碳水化合物吗？但是，你知道，
carbohydrates and sugar have been
碳水化合物和糖在
somewhat I guess demonized because you
某种程度上被妖魔化了，因为你
never really hear many good things about
很少听到关于
sugar.
糖的好话。
&gt;&gt; Um so so what is what is your goal here?
所以，你的目标是什么？你
What is the advice to the listener? Is
给听众的建议是什么？是
it to restrict their their
限制
carbohydrates?
碳水化合物的摄入吗？
&gt;&gt; To be very conscious of what they're
还是要非常注意自己的
consuming because nutrition has a
饮食，因为营养
powerful potent impact on overall
对整体健康有着强大的影响
health. And for those patients who have
？对于那些患有
chronic disease, which is unfortunately
慢性疾病的患者来说——不幸的是，这占了
the overwhelming majority of us, yes,
我们大多数人——是的，
carbohydrates can be a very restricting
碳水化合物可能是一个非常重要的限制因素。
carbohydrates can have a powerful
碳水化合物
therapeutic effect on diseases like type
对2型糖尿病等疾病具有强大的治疗作用
2 diabetes. The American Diabetes
。美国糖尿病
Association in their 2019 consensus
协会在其2019年的共识
report described type 2 diabetes as the
报告中指出，碳水化合物是目前
most evidence-based nutritional
循证营养
strategy. We know that it can have
策略中最具代表性的。我们知道，碳水化合物对阿尔茨海默病等疾病也可能产生
potential positive impacts on things
积极影响
like uh Alzheimer's disease. There are
。已有
studies that have looked at this. We
研究探讨了这一点。我们
also know that for
也知道，
&gt;&gt; carbohydrate restriction we
限制碳水化合物摄入可以改善整体健康状况。
&gt;&gt; Yep. So, and I like to term this
我喜欢把这种限制
therapeutic carbohydrate restriction
碳水化合物摄入称为“治疗性碳水化合物限制”，
because it's the therapeutic outcome of
因为它是
a carbohydrate reduction. Um and that's
减少碳水化合物摄入的治疗效果。而这才是其
really the goal of this is can you
真正的目标：能否
improve your overall health. Many people
改善整体健康状况。许多人这样
will just do this simply to improve, you
做只是为了改善自身状况，比如
know, to lose weight, to feel, like you
减肥，或者像你
say, to feel more cognitively alert. But
说的，感觉认知能力更强。但
in my case where you're along further
就我而言，如果你患有
diseases like diabetes, it has a even
糖尿病等代谢紊乱疾病，那么限制碳水化合物摄入
more uh potent impact on how you feel,
对你的感觉，
even more potent impact on your overall
对你的整体健康，会产生更显著的影响
health. Um, and but unfortunately about
。不幸的是，正如多项研究和多个研究小组所指出的，约
93% of Americans have some form of
93%的美国人存在某种形式的
metabolic derangement, uh, as cited by
代谢紊乱
groups. You did a 10-year study on the
。 一项为期十年的研究，旨在探究
impact of the ketogenic diet on a
生酮饮食对一位
patient that had type 1 diabetes. I
1型糖尿病患者的影响。我
think this is this is most certainly the
认为这无疑是迄今为止
longest study ever done of its type
同类研究中持续时间最长的，研究人员
where you took one individual and over
选取了一位受试者，并在长达
10 years you I guess controlled their
十年的时间里控制其
diet. So, we had access to
饮食。我们得以
the ability to monitor uh a unique
监测一位独特的
patient who had type 1 diabetes and they
1型糖尿病患者，该患者
were diagnosed and had followed the
确诊后遵循了
American Diabetes Association diet, a
美国糖尿病协会推荐的
healthy diet for 6 years and then
健康饮食方案长达六年，然后
switched over in 2013 to a ketogenic
在2013年开始尝试生酮
diet. Upon the initiation of the diet
饮食。在开始生酮饮食
and post, they had DEXA scans. They
前后，患者均接受了双能X线吸收仪（DEXA）扫描。他们
controlled their calorie intake, their
控制了卡路里摄入量和
body composition. they weren't taking
身体成分，没有服用
any additional medications and we were
任何其他药物。我们得以
while controlling all those variables.
在控制所有这些变量的情况下，监测生酮饮食对患者的影响长达十年之久。这项研究
And why that's so important is because
之所以如此重要，是因为人们
one of the common concerns of a
对生酮饮食的一个常见担忧
ketogenic diet is the hypothetical risk
是
it can increase cardiovascular disease.
它可能增加心血管疾病的风险。人们认为生酮饮食会增加心血管疾病风险，
cardiovascular disease or it's
或者说人们假设生酮饮食会增加心血管疾病风险，
hypothesized that it will is because of
是因为生酮饮食会导致低密度脂蛋白
the elevation in LDL that often
胆固醇（LDL）水平升高。
in the diet. Now saturated fat comes
饮食中饱和脂肪的增加也会导致心血管健康问题。饱和脂肪主要
from things like animal proteins, uh
来源于动物蛋白，
it's in coconuts as well. What we found
椰子中也含有饱和脂肪。我们发现，
is that despite a near doubling in LDL
尽管
cholesterol on this diet, which again
这种饮食导致低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL-C）几乎翻倍（这通常
should be associated with worsening
与
cardiovascular health, we did an
心血管健康恶化相关），但我们
advanced cardiovascular assessment in in
对这位患者进行了高级心血管评估，
this patient and found that despite
发现尽管
doubling LDL, they had maintained
LDL-C翻倍，他们的
completely normal glycemic control,
血糖控制却完全正常。
which again based on all the data says
根据所有数据，血糖控制
is the number one risk factor. They
是首要风险因素。他们
reduced their insulin load over 40%.
的胰岛素负荷降低了40%以上。
And their cardiovascular health was not
他们的心血管健康状况
only better than the average patient of
不仅优于
similar age and sex with type 1
同年龄同性别的1型
diabetes, it was better in almost every
糖尿病患者，而且几乎在
single category than people even without
所有方面都优于非
type 1 diabetes.
1型糖尿病患者。
despite the doubling of LDL cholesterol,
尽​​管LDL-C翻倍，
it illustrated that over a 10-ear
但这表明，在10年的
period, it maintained not only no sign
时间里，他们不仅没有出现任何
of cardiovascular disease, but
心血管疾病的迹象，而且
remarkable cardiovascular health. And
心血管健康状况非常出色。
and in fact, we actually followed on
事实上，我们随后开展了一项
that study with the largest ever
迄今为止规模最大的研究，
analysis of the impact of nutrition,
分析了营养（
particularly carbohydrates, in over
尤其是碳水化合物）对超过
46,000 patients with type 1 diabetes. We
46,000名1型糖尿病患者的影响。我们
showed that in over 70% of all reports
发现…… 超过70%的
of very low carbohydrate ketogenic diets
极低碳水化合物生酮饮食报告显示，
that patients were completely able to
患者能够完全
normalize their glucose control,
恢复血糖控制正常，使
for disease of type 1 diabetes.
1型糖尿病最主要的危险因素——糖化血红蛋白（HbA1c）——恢复正常。
&gt;&gt; And is this this is a sort of a spectrum
这就像一个连续谱，
of I'll put that on the screen for
我会把它显示在屏幕上，让
people to see the different sort of
大家看到
normal, pre-diabetic, and diabetic.
正常、糖尿病前期和糖尿病的不同阶段和分类。对
Right.
。没错。是的
&gt;&gt; Correct. Yes. So normal is anything less
。正常是指
than 5.7% HBA1C. Pre-diabetic is that
HbA1c低于5.7%。糖尿病前期是
5.7 number up to 6.4. And then diabetic
指5.7%到6.4%。而糖尿病
is anywhere between 6.5 all the way up
是指6.5%到6.4%之间，
into essentially uh there's no cap on
实际上，
how high that number can go. I
这个数值没有上限。
&gt;&gt; I mean I noticed your your blood sugar
我注意到您的血糖
levels have uh risen quite dramatically
水平已经显著升高
to
到这个程度
&gt;&gt; that. So what you see initially is is
。所以您最初看到的
probably only the first phase of this,
可能只是第一阶段，
right? So started at an average of
对吧？最初的平均血糖水平
around 100 milligs per deciliter on
约为每分升100毫克
average. And once the food is then
。食物被
consumed cuz once you consume the food
摄入后，由于
it takes some time to break down into
需要一些时间才能分解，血糖水平会进一步升高。
glucose that glucose then goes into the
葡萄糖会进入
blood and then the blood then moves
血液，然后血液会将
glucose into this compartment around the
葡萄糖输送到细胞周围的组织
fluid. And now we're starting to see the
液中。现在我们开始看到，
direct impact of just consuming probably
仅仅摄入相当于
a fifth of the amount of carbohydrates I
我每日所需碳水化合物五分之一的
should consume from a superfood. Um this
超级食物就能产生直接影响。
you know oranges are considered both a
你知道，橙子既是
citrus in a fruit and this is considered
柑橘类水果，也被
like a superfood by the American
美国
Diabetes Association uh in the context
糖尿病协会视为
of diabetes.
糖尿病患者的超级食物。
&gt;&gt; So when the glucose spike is high, so
所以，当
you've just eaten some oranges, the
你吃了一些橙子后，
spike is going up.
血糖会飙升。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的，
What does someone feel and then what do
你会有什么感觉？然后血糖
they feel when it's then crashes down
骤降到100以下时，你又会有什么感觉
and goes below? Because it started at
？因为血糖最初在
about 100. So I imagine that it's going
100左右。所以我估计它会上
to go up to whatever it goes up to and
升到某个数值，
then it's not going to drop back down to
然后不会回落到
100. It's going to drop below 100
100。
typically in a in a normal um
通常情况下，对于正常的
non-diabetic person, right?
非糖尿病患者来说，血糖会降到100以下，对吧？
&gt;&gt; So 100's right around the uh normal. So
100左右是正常的血糖值。所以，
what you'd hope would happen is that
你希望…… 实际情况是，
you're going to go up just a little bit,
你的血糖会略微升高，
insulin's going to respond quickly, and
胰岛素会迅速做出反应，然后血糖就会
you're going to come back down to
回落到
normal. if you have total healthy
正常水平。前提是你拥有完全健康的
metabolic function. Again, the vast
代谢功能。当然，
majority of us do not. But in this case,
我们绝大多数人并非如此。但在这种情况下，
what's going to what would be predicted
可以预见的
to happen is that as blood sugar
是，随着血糖
elevates and insulin responds,
升高，胰岛素会做出反应，血糖值会达到
of glucose that's present in the food.
食物中葡萄糖含量的峰值。
Okay? But at the same time, the my pod
明白吗？与此同时，我的胰岛素泵（
is also which is holding my insulin is
储存胰岛素的装置）也会
immediately trying to respond. it's
立即做出反应。它会
immediately trying to say, "Okay, oh no,
立即发出信号：“糟糕，
we need to bring this and keep this into
我们需要将血糖控制在
a normal range." Um, and so it's trying
正常范围内。” 因此，它会尝试
to release insulin. And so you can see
释放胰岛素。所以你可以
on the screen that there's this massive
在屏幕上看到
uptick in the blue line, which is the
蓝线出现了一个大幅上升，这是
initial response in insulin immediately
胰岛素
to the elevation in glucose. This is
对血糖升高的初始反应。这正是
exactly what happens in normal
正常
physiology. Yet no one can measure it,
生理状态下发生的情况。虽然没有人能够测量到这种反应，
but you can see it here.
但你可以在这里看到它。
&gt;&gt; So how would I feel when the glucose
那么，当血糖飙升时，我会有什么感觉呢
spike is high? Do I feel energetic? Do I
？ 感觉精力充沛吗？我
feel focused? Or do I feel tired? My
感觉注意力集中吗？还是感觉疲惫？
personal experience here Stephen is that
斯蒂芬，就我个人经验而言，
as blood sugar becomes very high I
当血糖过高时，我的
become my focus reduces my I become
注意力会下降，我会感到
fatigued. Uh I can also according to my
疲倦。嗯，据我
wife become irritable. Um and but you
妻子说，我还会变得易怒。嗯，你
can even look this up you know you can
甚至可以查一下，你可以
look up what are the symptoms of
查一下低血糖的症状，以及
elevated glucose levels above the normal
血糖水平高于正常
range which is normal 70 to 120. That's
范围（70到120）的症状。这时
when you can start to see uh very
你就能
clearly that the evidence over time has
清楚地看到，随着时间的推移，证据表明，血糖过高
shown a a very clear impact on not only
不仅会对你的身体状况产生非常明显的影响，还会影响
how you feel physically but also your
你的
mental health status as well. Oh, I've
心理健康。哦，我
just looked up the symptoms here and it
刚刚查了一下这些症状，上面
says um the common immediate symptoms of
说，血糖飙升的常见即时症状包括：
thirsty, dry mouth, um frequent
口渴、口干、
urination, headache, brain fog, fatigue,
尿频、头痛、思维迟钝、疲劳、反应迟钝、
sluggishness, blurry vision. Um,
视力模糊。嗯，
and then once you go down and you crash
然后，一旦血糖下降，
or your glucose really drops below the
或者血糖真的
normal range, what do you feel then?
低于正常范围，你会有什么感觉呢？
Typically,
通常情况下，
&gt;&gt; so a lot of how I like to describe this
我喜欢这样描述……
is almost like imagine you're outside
这就像想象一下，你身处户外，
and it's sunny outside and you're having
阳光明媚，
a great day, great conversation with
和朋友们聊得正开心，度过了美好的一天，
other friends, and then all of a sudden,
突然间，
very rapidly, clouds come over top.
乌云迅速笼罩大地。
Everyone kind of dissipates and it
大家仿佛都散开了，
starts to rain. It's almost like it's
开始下雨。这就像……
it's we know that glucose levels have a
我们知道血糖水平
direct impact on the neurobiology of the
直接影响大脑的神经生物学
brain. Meaning how the brain functions,
。也就是说，它会影响大脑的功能和
how it operates, and particularly at
运作方式，尤其是在
very high glucose levels, you know,
血糖水平非常高的时候，比如
typically above 180 milligs per
通常高于每
deciliter, you start to see signals of
分升180毫克，就会出现
inflammation, signals of stress, like
炎症信号和应激信号，比如
oxidative stress in the body if people
氧化应激（如果有人
have heard of that before. And that can
听说过的话）。这会
start to cause damage on tissues and
开始损伤组织，
cause a stress response. But the problem
引发应激反应。但是
here, Stephen, is that most patients are
，斯蒂芬，问题在于大多数患者
living there 24/7.
24小时都处于这种状态。
&gt;&gt; I was looking at some of the symptoms
我查看了一些症状
here, and it says the short-term crash
，上面说，血糖
you get after a spike, um, after a rapid
飙升后出现的短期低血糖，也就是
is a bit of an insulin overshoot. So,
胰岛素过量，
it's reactive hypoglycemia, which is the
是反应性低血糖，也就是
sugar crash. And then you might feel in
血糖骤降。然后你可能会……
that crash jittery or shaky, hungry,
那种崩溃的感觉就像神经紧张、浑身发抖、饥饿难耐，
often craving carbs and sugar again,
经常又渴望碳水化合物和糖分，
irritable, anxious, weak, or
易怒、焦虑、虚弱或
lightheaded. I stayed up until 3:00 a.m.
头晕目眩。
the night I first tried Replet, and it
我第一次尝试 Replet 的那天晚上，熬夜到凌晨三点，它彻底
blew my mind. Replet, our sponsor of
震撼了我。Replet 是我们播客的赞助商
this podcast, are one of the most
，也是
powerful AI platforms I've come across.
我见过的最强大的 AI 平台之一。
They allow you to turn any idea you have
它能让你
into real working apps in minutes using
用简单的英语，在几分钟内将任何想法变成真正可用的应用程序
plain English. Just describe what you
。你只需描述你
want to create and Replet's AI agents
想创建的内容，Replet 的 AI 代理
will create it for you. And you don't
就会为你创建。而且你
need any coding experience to get
无需任何编程经验即可
started. I asked Replet's AI agent to
上手。我让 Replet 的 AI 代理
based on exactly how I wanted my perfect
根据我理想中的完美
to-do list to be. And it built it for me
待办事项清单，为我创建一个全新的清单。它只用了
in minutes, and I didn't need to know
几分钟就完成了，而且我不需要任何
how to code to create it. That is now
编程知识就能创建它。现在
the to-do list that I'm using. Super
我正在使用这个待办事项清单。它超级
cheap, super fast, and completely
便宜、超级快速，而且完全根据
personalized to exactly what I wanted it
我的需求进行了个性化定制
to do. And now I'm an investor in the
。现在我也是 Replet 的投资者了。
company as well as them being a brand
公司不仅是品牌
sponsor. And Replic connects to payment
赞助商，而且Replic还能连接到
systems like Stripe or services like
Stripe等支付系统或
OpenAI and has a built-in database and
OpenAI等服务，并内置数据库和
user authentication system. If you're a
用户身份验证系统。如果您是
founder or a freelancer or anyone who's
创始人、自由职业者或任何
been searching for someone who can code,
正在寻找程序员的人，
you can build your next app with Replet.
您可以使用Replet构建您的下一个应用程序。
Head to replet.com and use code Steven
访问replet.com并使用代码Steven，
to get 50% off your first month of
即可享受Replet核心计划首月50%的折扣
Replet's core plan. You did a study in
。我相信您在2025年做过一项关于
ketogenic diet on physical performance.
生酮饮食对运动表现影响的研究。
you know, if the ketogenic diet has all
要知道，如果生酮饮食具有所有
these therapeutic potentials, you know,
这些治疗潜力，而且可以
going back for over two centuries, what
追溯到两个多世纪以前，那么
is truly the impact of it on
它对运动表现的真正影响是什么
performance? Because that's one of the
？因为这是
primary reasons where someone were to
人们
walk into a a clinical setting and say,
走进诊所说
"Well, yeah, you can do this, but I've
“是的，你可以这样做，但我
heard it's going to decrease my
听说它会降低我的运动
performance."
表现”的主要原因之一。
&gt;&gt; Physical performance.
运动表现。
&gt;&gt; Physical performance. And so we were
运动表现。所以我们
very very interested in this because we
对此非常感兴趣，因为我们
thought okay
想，好吧，
you know when we look at why
你知道，当我们研究为什么
carbohydrates are currently being
碳水化合物目前被
recommended as sports nutrition is
推荐为运动营养时，它是否也对运动表现产生了影响。 营养之所以重要，是
because since 1921 they've been shown to
因为自1921年以来，研究表明它能
improve performance and how they showed
提高运动表现。1921年的研究是如何得出这一结论的呢？当时，
Harvard and um and Boston actually
哈佛大学和波士顿的医生
watched Boston marathoners half of which
观察了波士顿马拉松的参赛者，发现其中一半人
who would come wouldn't even finish the
甚至无法完成
race slurred words they would uh have
比赛。他们说话含糊不清，
like almost pale skin, shaky, weren't
脸色苍白，浑身颤抖，无法清晰地
able to articulate their words or some
表达自己的想法，有些人甚至根本
wouldn't finish at all. And what they
无法完成比赛。医生们
were finding was that these when they
发现，当他们
tested the blood of these individuals
检测这些参赛者的血液时，
that they were finding that glucose
发现他们的血糖
levels were low. Basically, they reached
水平很低。基本上，他们达到了
what they call hypoglycemia. It's a
所谓的低血糖症，这是一个
medical term to describe very low blood
医学术语，用来描述极低的
sugar levels. And
血糖水平。
then next year they provided
第二年，他们为
carbohydrates and these marathoners in
这些参加
the Boston Marathon and all of them
波士顿马拉松的选手补充了碳水化合物，结果所有选手的
improve their performance. And so since
成绩都得到了提高。因此，
192 or 1925 actually we've known that
实际上从1925年起，我们就知道
carbohydrates can improve performance.
碳水化合物可以提高运动表现。
But we what has happened though over
但随着
time is that in 1960s
时间的推移，到了20世纪60年代，
we there was a measurement technique
出现了一种
called the Birdstrom method where you
叫做伯德斯特罗姆法的测量技术，这种方法通过
actually did a muscle biopsy pulled out
肌肉活检，取出
muscle tissue and found that oh wow
肌肉组织样本进行分析。 研究发现，
muscle. So it must be really important
肌肉中竟然储存着葡萄糖。这说明葡萄糖
for physical performance. If the muscle
对运动表现至关重要。如果肌肉组织中含有
glucose is in that tissue, it must be
葡萄糖，那么它
essential for performance. And then
对于运动表现就必不可少。之后，研究人员
after they discovered that there was all
发现
levels in the muscle called glycogen,
肌肉中葡萄糖含量低（称为
low glycogen and fatigue. Then after
糖原含量低）与疲劳之间存在关联。到了
that the in the 1980s they were able to
20世纪80年代，他们开始
look at the amount of
研究运动过程中
sugar, carbohydrates and fat that the
人体燃烧的糖、碳水化合物和脂肪的量
body was burning during exercise. And
。
what they found at that stage is that oh
他们发现，
people are able to sustain intense
人们能够持续进行高强度
exercise is proportional to how many
运动的程度似乎与
carbohydrates they're burning.
他们燃烧的碳水化合物量成正比。
And then there was a few modeling
随后，一些建模
studies Stephen that then looked at okay
研究探讨了
let's say uh the intensity of exercise
运动强度
and what type of fuel you use whether it
与燃料类型（
be fat or carbohydrates
脂肪或碳水化合物）之间的关系。
and they found that they modeled it okay
他们建立模型后发现，在
and said okay well at lower intensities
低强度运动中，人体
you must burn almost all fat and at very
几乎燃烧所有脂肪；而在
high intensities you must burn carbs and
高强度运动中，人体则燃烧碳水化合物。
there was a number of studies in 2017 to
2017年至
2020, three different studies that
2020年间的多项研究，包括三项不同的研究，
looked at the ketogenic diet over a 5day
考察了生酮饮食在5天
to 3 week period. And they saw that in
至3周内的影响。
those studies that there was a decline
研究发现，生酮饮食会导致
in performance by around 2%.
运动表现下降约2%。
&gt;&gt; correct? Compared to a high carb diet.
矩形？ 与高碳水化合物饮食相比。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; And so what did that tell these
那么，这告诉了这些
researchers? Well, it said, "Okay, well
研究人员什么呢？ 它说：“好吧，很
obviously the ketogenic diet must impair
显然，生酮饮食一定会损害
performance." And there's all this
运动表现。”
evidence since 1921s that the amount of
自 1921 年以来，有大量证据表明，
carbohydrates, glycogen, how much carbs
碳水化合物、糖原的含量，以及
you're you're consuming is essential
你摄入的碳水化合物量，对运动
performance. But here's the kicker is
表现至关重要。 但关键在于，
one major confounder of all this is that
所有这一切的一个主要混淆因素是，
we've known for quite a long period of
我们早就知道，
time that the adaptation to a ketogenic
适应生酮
diet is not one week, it's not two
饮食不是一周，不是
weeks, not even three, it's four weeks
两周，甚至不是三周，而是四周
or more. And when you say adaptation,
或更长时间。 而你所说的适应，
you mean your body's transition to being
指的是你的身体过渡到能够
in a a state where it's efficient at
高效
burning using ketones.
利用酮体燃烧脂肪的状态。
&gt;&gt; So the body's ability to
因此，由于你给身体提供的碳水化合物减少，身体就能
lower its glucose oxidation or the
降低葡萄糖氧化率，或者说降低身体
amount of carbohydrates it's burning for
燃烧碳水化合物作为燃料的量
less of it. The amount of fat that's
。 被用作能量的脂肪量
dramatically. And then you produce way
急剧增加。 然后你会产生
more ketone bodies. And ketones are now
更多的酮体。 酮类物质现在
being used as not only a a body uh
不仅被用作身体
tissue substrate meaning energy for the
组织底物（即
muscle but also for the brain. And so
肌肉的能量来源），也被用作大脑的能量来源。
it's this transition over. But when
过渡期就此结束。 但当
people were looking at these studies
人们研究这些研究时，
they were just looking at some of the
他们只是在观察
metrics of what happens when you your
当
body transforms when you reduce
你减少碳水化合物摄入时身体发生哪些变化的一些指标
carbohydrates.
。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So what we wanted to do is say,
好的。 所以我们想说的是，
okay, if there's all these
好吧，如果生
healthpromoting benefits of a ketogenic
酮饮食有这么多促进健康的好处
diet, that sounds great, but all these
，那听起来很棒，但是所有这些
studies and sports dogma would say
研究和体育界的教条都说，
that's going to impair performance.
这会损害运动表现。
Okay, so let's test that. Let's actually
好的，那我们来测试一下。 让我们
put athletes on a ketogenic diet for 4
让运动员们进行为期 4 周的生酮饮食
weeks. We are going to control not only
。 我们不仅要控制
their calories, we're going to control
他们的卡路里摄入量，还要控制
their body composition, we're going to
他们的身体成分，还要
control their activity level. We're
控制他们的活动水平。 我们
going to control all these key
将控制所有这些关键的
confounders that many of these prior
混杂因素，而许多先前的
studies never controlled so that we
研究从未控制过这些因素，以便我们
could truly test the diet induced so the
能够真正测试饮食引起的
macronutrient meaning the shift from
宏量营养素（即从
carbs to fat effect on performance but
碳水化合物到脂肪的转变）对运动表现的影响，但
we're going to do it in the same person.
我们将在同一个人身上进行测试。
So now we're going to control their
所以现在我们要控制它们的
genetics. We're going to control their
基因。 我们将控制他们的
environment. Once we did that, Stephen,
环境。 斯蒂芬，我们完成那件事之后，
we tested what most people think is a,
就测试了大多数人认为的那种
you know, a very glucose dependent form
非常依赖葡萄糖的
of exercise. We asked them to do 6 by
运动形式。 我们要求他们进行 6 组
800 meter sprints. They were on a high
800 米短跑。 他们之前一直吃高
carb diet and then they switched to a
碳水化合物饮食，后来改吃
low carb diet. Now, what happened this
低碳水化合物饮食。 现在，这一切的发生都是
is all randomized uh and controlled.
随机的，并且是受控的。
When they switched over,
当他们进行转换后，
&gt;&gt; at four weeks. at the four-week mark in
四周内他们的表现没有下降。 四周后，
a form of exercise that we would expect
我们预计这种运动形式
would be extremely glucose dependent,
将非常依赖葡萄糖和
extremely carbohydrate dependent.
碳水化合物。
&gt;&gt; But before 4 weeks, was there an
但在 4 周之前，
impairment in their performance?
他们的表现是否受到影响？
&gt;&gt; So what we were interested in, Stephen,
所以，斯蒂芬，我们感兴趣的
is studying at the end. So we didn't
是最后阶段的研究。 所以我们没有进行
look intermediately. We exclusively look
中间阶段的考察。 我们只
at the end time point because the the
关注最终时间点，因为
question was, well, if is there a
问题是，
difference once you stick to this diet?
坚持这种饮食方式后是否会有区别？
Because if you you go on this diet,
因为如果你选择这种饮食方式，
ideally you're you're sticking with it
理想情况下你应该能够
over time. And so
长期坚持下去。 因此，
if it is true that you require
如果确实需要
carbohydrates, we then also measured how
碳水化合物，我们还测量了
many carbohydrates and fat they were
他们
burning during exercise.
在运动过程中燃烧了多少碳水化合物和脂肪。
And it was over what we call 85% of
而且超过了
their V2 max, which means 85% of their
他们最大摄氧量的 85%，这意味着他们运动
total maximum oxygen consumption during
期间总最大摄氧量的 85%
exercise.
。
That is when we would expect almost no
那时我们预计几乎没有
fat to be oxidized or to be burned and
脂肪会被氧化或燃烧，而
almost exclusively carbohydrates. Well,
几乎全部是碳水化合物。
we found that these athletes recorded
我们发现，这些运动员
the highest levels of fat burning during
在运动过程中记录到了文献报道过的最高脂肪燃烧水平
literature, illustrating that when these
，这表明，当这些
athletes,
运动员
adapted to the diet for sufficiently
适应生酮饮食足够
long, they had record levels of fat
长的时间后，即使在非常高的强度水平下，他们的脂肪氧化水平也达到了创纪录的水平
levels. which means that fat was able to
。 这意味着
provide nutrients and fuel at very very
在非常非常剧烈的运动中，脂肪能够提供营养和能量，
intense forms of exercise when we would
而我们通常
expect only carbohydrates would be
认为只有碳水化合物才是
relevant and utilizable.
相关的和可利用的。
So many of my friends um that are
我的很多朋友，比如
endurance athletes or that are involved
耐力运动员或者从事
in things like cycling talk about
自行车运动的人，都在谈论
exogenous ketones. Um I'm a co-owner of
外源性酮。 嗯，我是
a company that produces exogenous
一家生产外源性
ketones. That's my disclaimer. I've got
酮类化合物的公司的共同所有人。 这是我的免责声明。
the product here. What can you tell me
产品在这里。 您能跟我说说
about products like this? Exogenous
这类产品吗？ 外源性
ketone products. Exogenous meaning
酮类产物。 外源性是指
externally supplemented, I guess,
外部补充，
&gt;&gt; right? So, with a ketogenic diet, you
对吧？ 所以，通过生酮饮食，你就会
produce them. Your liver produces them
产生它们。 你的肝脏会
for you. With um exogenous, you're
为你产生它们。 嗯，这些是外源性的，你正在
consuming these. Well, why would you
摄入它们。 那你为什么要
consume them? Why not just do a
食用它们呢？ 为什么不直接采用
ketogenic diet? Well, we know that a
生酮饮食呢？ 我们知道，
ketogenic diet
生酮饮食
takes time to adapt. We just talked
需要时间适应。 我们刚才谈到了
about that with physical performance
身体机能方面的问题，
that we see that you know up to four
我们发现，要
weeks to see the full effect on on
看到对表现的全面影响，可能需要长达四周
performance or more. Well, what happens
甚至更长时间。 那么，
if you're let's say a war fighter or
如果你是一名作战人员，或者即将
someone who's going out into the field
奔赴战场，
or immediately wants to flip into this
或者想要立即转入这种
state? You can't do that unless there
状态，会发生什么呢？ 除非有
was a molecule that you could consume
一种分子可以被摄入，并
in circulation within minutes.
在几分钟内迅速提高血液循环中的酮体水平，否则你无法做到这一点。
Insert exogenous ketone bodies. We have
加入外源性酮体。 我们
known since the 1960s
从 20 世纪 60 年代就知道，
MIT uh in the aerospace department
麻省理工学院航空航天系研究过其中的产品，它被
called 13butane dial. It that it was
称为 13-丁烷。 它
able to be consumed and rapidly elevate
能够被人体摄入并迅速提高
ketone bodies in circulation. There was
血液循环中的酮体水平。
a study in 2016 called the metabolic
2016 年，DARPA 启动了一项名为“代谢
optimization $10 million program from
优化”的 1000 万美元计划
DARPA. DARPA being the
。  DARPA 是
organization from the United States
美国政府下属的高级研究机构，
government where they fund very high
它资助高
risk high reward programs and one of
风险高回报的项目，其中之一
which was the the the use and testing of
就是酮体的使用和测试
ketone bodies. And so that uh molecule
。 所以
that they tested was um utilized the
他们测试的那个分子，嗯，利用了
same molecule that's in there and they
里面的同一种分子，他们
formulations a bit and they showed that
稍微调整了一些配方，结果表明，
and we know that this is the same for
我们知道这种
this molecule as well that when you
分子也是如此，当你
consume them it rapidly changes
服用它时，它会迅速改变
metabolism almost uh not identical to
新陈代谢，虽然不完全等同
what happens with the ketogenic diet but
于生酮饮食，但
it has a almost direct impact. It has a
它几乎有直接的影响。 它具有
blood glucose lowering effect. it
降低血糖的作用。 它
directly binds to receptors like the um
直接与受体结合，例如
they call GPR 109A or uh or some other
他们称之为 GPR 109A 的受体，或者其他一些
key receptors that directly uh impact
直接影响炎症的关键受体
inflammation. So it directly blocks
。 因此，它直接阻断了
something called NLRP3 inflammosome
一种叫做 NLRP3 炎症小体的物质，
which is a molecule that leads to
这种分子会导致
increases in inflammation. We also know
炎症加剧。 我们还知道，
that it changes the way that our genes
它会改变我们
are used in the body called epigenetic
体内基因的使用方式，这被称为表观遗传
signaling. And so the uh consumption of
信号传导。 因此，酮体的摄入
ketone bodies can actually change the
实际上可以改变
molecules on our genes and and how those
我们基因上的分子以及这些
molecules are ultimately manifested and
分子的最终表现方式，从而
that increases our antioxidant capacity
提高我们的抗氧化能力，这
meaning our ability to block oxidative
意味着我们阻止
stress in the body. We we see all these
体内氧化应激的能力。 我们看到了所有这些
powerful effects, these rapid shifts in
强大的影响，体内新陈代谢的这些快速变化
metabolism within the body. And this
。
2016 study showed that just orally
2016 年的一项研究表明，仅仅
consuming these molecules could rapidly
口服这些分子就能迅速
shift metabolism, but that it was also
改变新陈代谢，而且还能
linked to an improvement in physical
提高身体
performance. But if you look beyond that
机能。 但如果你更深入地了解这些研究，
studies because we looked at them in
比如我们在
athletes, we looked at them in healthy
运动员身上、在健康
individuals and then also in military
个体身上以及在军事
settings. But we've also there's studies
环境中进行的这类研究，就会发现问题所在。 但我们也有一些研究正在关注
cognitive decline. So patients at risk
认知能力下降风险患者的情况。 所以，有患
for Alzheimer's disease. They've shown
阿尔茨海默病风险的患者。 他们
that in a six-month study administering
在一项为期六个月的研究中表明，施用
exogenous uh ketone bodies was able to
外源性酮体能够
attenuate the decline in uh cognition
减缓
that we know happens with advanced age.
我们所知的随着年龄增长而发生的认知能力下降。   需要
&gt;&gt; And just to be clear there, you're
明确的是，你的
saying it reduces the decline. It
意思是它能减少衰退。 它既
doesn't
不能
&gt;&gt; cure Alzheimer's or fix Alzheimer's. It
治愈阿尔茨海默病，也不能修复阿尔茨海默病。 只会
just delays.
拖延时间。
&gt;&gt; Accurate. Yes. It's it's we know that as
准确的。 是的。 我们知道，随着
individuals age, you're on a precipitous
年龄的增长，
or or steady decline in in brain
大脑功能会急剧或持续下降
function. Um, and so the goal is to to
。 嗯，所以目标是
offset or to stop the decline. You know,
抵消或阻止这种下滑趋势。 你知道，
that's our goal. We want to maintain
那就是我们的目标。 我们希望保持
normal uh brain function and our ability
正常的脑功能，以及
to think clearly and to understand
清晰思考和理解
things clearly like reading and and
事物的能力，例如阅读、
doing problems and solving problems.
做题和解决问题。
studies in the world of psychiatry. I
精神病学领域也出现了类似的研究。 我
think there's around 11 ongoing active
认为目前大约有 11 项正在进行的
clinical trials looking at the impact
临床试验，研究
and interaction of ketonebased therapies
酮类疗法对
and brain health uh particularly serious
大脑健康，特别是严重
mental illness. One in four adults in
精神疾病的影响和相互作用。 美国四分之一的成年人（
the United States actually over one in
实际上超过四分之一）
four adults in the United States has
患有
serious mental illness. In fact, I
严重的精神疾病。 事实上，我
believe over the numbers are over 20% of
相信超过 20% 的
of adults are taking some type of psycho
成年人正在服用某种类型的精神
uh altering medication. At its core, we
药物。 从本质上讲，我们
see all these relationships
认为所有这些关系都
between underlying metabolism being a
与潜在的新陈代谢有关，而新陈代谢是
factor contributing to mental health
影响心理健康
status. and the application of the this
状况的关键因素。
unique diet which we know increases
我们知道，这种独特的饮食可以增加
ketone bodies which appear to have
酮体，而酮体似乎
direct impacts on the brain now seems to
对大脑有直接影响。现在看来，这种饮食与
be linked to improved serious mental
严重精神疾病的改善有关。
illness and it'll be interesting to see
看看它未来的
where the that evolves but it's just a
发展方向会很有趣，但
fascinating world to imagine that
想象一下，
nutrition not a medication not a
营养，而不是药物或
technology but the the simply going to
技术，仅仅是去
the grocery store and swapping the
杂货店，替换
things you choose in there can lead to
你选择的食材，就能对
effects um in people of all sorts of
各种
different conditions uh or disorders.
不同疾病或障碍患者产生如此强大的治疗效果，这真是一个令人着迷的世界。
&gt;&gt; On one of the studies that I read about
我读过一篇关于
the administration of exogenous ketones
外源性酮类物质的施用
and the impact it has on brain network
及其对大脑网络
stability was from 2020 where they
稳定性的影响的研究，该研究发表于 2020 年，研究者
investigated if brain network stability
调查了大脑网络稳定性是否会对
responds to two major brain fuels either
两种主要的大脑燃料——
glucose or ketones. And participants
葡萄糖或酮类物质——做出反应。 参与者分
came to the laboratory on two occasions
两次来到实验室，分别
and drank exogenous ketones or glucose.
饮用外源性酮或葡萄糖。
And after cons consuming these drinks,
受试者饮用这些饮料后，
they underwent an MRI scan. Strikingly,
接受了核磁共振扫描。 令人惊讶的是，
the study showed that ketones increased
该研究表明酮类物质可以提高
the stability of brain networks. In
大脑网络的稳定性。
contrast, glucose decreased the
相反，葡萄糖降低了
stability of the network. The network
网络的稳定性。
stability was 87% greater after ketone
酮体消耗后网络稳定性
consumption than stability measured
比
after glucose consumption. And in that
葡萄糖消耗后测得的稳定性高 87%。 在
study which is on PubMed, the last line
PubMed上发表的那项研究中，摘要的最后一行
of the abstract says, "Dietary
写道：“
interventions resulting in ketone
通过饮食干预
utilization increase available energy
提高酮体利用率可以增加可用能量，
and thus may show potential in
因此可能具有
protecting the aging of the brain which
延缓大脑衰老的潜力，这
is super interesting.
非常有趣。”
&gt;&gt; So we did a study uh looking at cancer
我们做了一项研究，观察癌症，
and applying exogenous ketones and a
并应用外源性酮体治疗一种侵袭性
very aggressive form of metastatic
很强的转移性
cancer. And what we saw in in my work in
癌症。我在
graduate school is that when applying
研究生阶段的研究中发现，应用
disogenous ketones that it delayed the
外源性酮体可以延缓
progression of the metastatic cancer,
转移性癌症的进展，
but it also
同时还能
when looking at body weight reduced the
减少癌症患者常见的
rapid decline in body weight we
体重快速下降
sometimes see with cancer. A phenomenon
。这种现象
called cexia which is a way a term to
被称为萎缩，用来
describe the wa rapid wasting of body
描述疾病导致的身体组织快速消耗
tissue with disease. And it is no more
。萎缩并不
aggressive than the context of cancer
比癌症更具侵袭性，
particularly metastatic cancer is where
尤其是在转移性癌症中
it's most common and when we saw the
最为常见。当我们观察到
lack of decline in body weight I then
体重没有下降时，我进一步
looked at where the body weight was
研究了体重的来源，结果发现
lack of body weight decline
体重没有下降
was because of the preservation of in
是因为
muscle mass. So it also appeared and
肌肉质量得以保留。此外，还有一些
clinical physiology studies. those
临床生理学研究也证实了这一点。
studies that actually directly
实际上，这些研究直接利用
manipulate human beings with molecules
分子
and tests, you know, like muscle tissues
和测试手段来操控人体，比如肌肉组织
and how they function. We see that
及其功能。我们发现，
exogenous ketone administration can
外源性酮的补充可以
dramatically reduce the amount of muscle
显著减少肌肉
breakdown uh or breakdown of muscle
分解，或者说肌肉
tissue. Uh essentially illustrating it
组织的分解。这实际上表明，它
may be a powerful mechanism in promoting
可能也是促进
healthy muscle mass as well. In terms of
健康肌肉质量的有效机制。
being in a ketogenic diet, one of the
说到生酮饮食，
things I'm always quite concerned about
我一直很担心的一点
is am I still able to gain muscle mass
是，
if I'm in a ketogenic diet? Because I
如果我采用生酮饮食，还能增加肌肉吗？因为，
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I when I go into a ketogenic diet
是的，当我开始生酮饮食，
and I stop having carbohydrates, I tend
停止摄入碳水化合物时，我的
to lose weight rapidly and shred.
体重往往会迅速下降，肌肉线条也会变得很明显。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的，
&gt;&gt; The fats falls off and I get very lean
脂肪会减少，我会变得非常精瘦，
but
但
&gt;&gt; yeah,
确实
&gt;&gt; more skinny.
更瘦了。
&gt;&gt; You smiled though because maybe you like
不过你笑了，也许你喜欢肌肉
to be more shredded. Um, so a phenomenon
线条更清晰的身材。嗯，这是
with the ketogenic diet. So there's no
生酮饮食的一个现象。生酮饮食不会导致
deterioration in muscle mass with the
肌肉质量下降
ketogenic diet. There have been plenty
。已经有很多研究表明，生酮饮食
able to maintain muscle mass
能够维持
&gt;&gt; and build it.
并增加肌肉质量。
&gt;&gt; Yes. And build it. So they've shown that
是的，还能增加肌肉。他们也证明了这一点
as well. So Jeff Volic out of Ohio State
。俄亥俄州立大学的杰夫·沃利克（Jeff Volic）也证实了这一点。
University has done a number of studies
大学在这方面做了很多研究
in this area. Um, looking at individuals
。他们观察了一些
reduced intake diet. So they're reducing
减少饮食摄入量的人，也就是
less calories. So they had less energy
减少了卡路里摄入，也就是减少了能量
in the diet. And then they were also
摄入。同时，他们还
doing the ketogenic diet. It was
采用了生酮饮食。这是
actually a military study and they
一项军事研究，结果
showed that they were able to maintain
表明，
someone was on a high carb diet um while
在
under a caloric restriction or another
热量限制（或者
way of describing that is like a semi
说接近半
starving starvation state. So there's no
饥饿状态）的情况下，他们能够像高碳水化合物饮食者一样保持肌肉量。所以，
these diets on muscle mass. However, to
这些饮食方式对肌肉量没有负面影响。然而，就
your per your personal example, one of
你个人的例子而言，
the first things that happens when you
当你
go onto a ketogenic diet is there's a
开始生酮饮食时，首先会发生的就是一个
naturatic effect or natures effect, but
自然效应，也就是
basically you reduce the amount of
减少
sodium in the body. So, you you you p
体内钠的含量。钠会通过尿液排出体外，
you piss it out basically and um you so
从而
you hold less water weight and that's
减少体内水分，这是
one of the first things. That's why
最先发生的变化之一。这就是为什么
people see this rapid shift in body
人们在
weight initially when they're you know
开始生
on a ketogenic diet, which for many
酮饮食初期体重会迅速变化的原因，这对很多
people is great because if they're
人来说都是好事。 因为如果他们是为了减肥而
trying to do it to lose weight, that's
减重，这就
like immediate reinforcement. But
像是立即强化了减肥效果。但
sometimes it's water weight. Well, water
有时减掉的是水分。水分
is in both the fat and the muscle. So,
存在于脂肪和肌肉中。所以，
it's it's not necessarily that you're
你不一定是在
losing any muscle mass per se, but it
真正失去肌肉，而
just might be in a phenomena less water
只是体内水分减少了
weight. And in some context, that might
。在某些情况下，这可能
be beneficial. Right? If you're in a
是有益的。对吧？如果你从事的
sport where you have a
运动需要一定的
power toweight ratio, but you're able to
功率体重比，但你能够
weight simply by shifting water, that's
通过转移水分在较轻的体重下保持相同的功率，那就
great. Um, as long as you're able to
很棒了。只要你的
function equivalently. Is there anything
运动能力保持不变。那么，
I do need to be thinking about in terms
在饮食方面，我需要注意些什么来
of my diet to make sure I'm still
确保
gaining weight just to I guess to keep
体重增加，从而
to keep my protein levels high?
保持较高的蛋白质水平呢？就增肌而言
&gt;&gt; So, the most important thing related to
，饮食方面最重要的就是进行
build muscle mass is to exercise hard
高强度的
and with resistance exercise. Uh that's
阻力训练。这是
to your diet to enhance that effect.
饮食方面最重要的因素，可以增强增肌效果。
Protein is one of the the most powerful
蛋白质是
nutrients you can consume to augment
增强增肌
that response. Another is to ensure
效果最有效的营养素之一。另一个是…… 为了确保
you're having uh sufficient
你摄入足够的
calories. Right? So if you're in a
热量，对吧？所以如果你处于
caloric deficit, so you said that you
热量缺口状态，就像你说的，你
know you tend to eat less calories
知道你往往会吃得更少，
because you're probably not as hungry.
因为你可能没那么饿。
Um well, yes, that's one of the most
嗯，是的，这是
powerful ways to lose not only fat but
减脂和
also muscle is to just not eat food or
减肌最有效的方法之一，那就是不吃东西，或者
&gt;&gt; I think that's it because I I lose my
我想就是这样，因为
appetite when I when I'm in the
我在生
ketogenic diet.
酮饮食期间会失去食欲。
when I take these um exogenous ketones
当我服用
like Ketone IQ.
像 Ketone IQ 这样的外源性酮时，我的食欲也会稍微下降。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And I've seen some of the studies
是的。我看到一些研究
that show that there's roughly 20%
表明，根据我读过的一项研究，
when you take exogenous ketones
服用外源性酮会使食欲下降约 20%。
read. But when I when I'm in the
但是当我进行
ketogenic diet, I it's like food is I
生酮饮食时，我对食物的感觉是，我会
get hungry but then I start eating and I
感到饥饿，但当我开始吃东西时，我
stop very quickly.
很快就停止了。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And it's really bizarre. Like I was I
这真的很奇怪。比如，我
was in Cape Town for 10 days or two
在开普敦待了 10 天或 2
weeks writing my book. And so I had the
周来写我的书。所以我在
chef there and the chef cooks me my food
那里有一位厨师，他 他给我做饭，
and makes this amazing food and I'm so
做得特别好吃，我饿得
hungry. I look at it I'm like amazing. I
不行。看着就觉得棒极了。我
start eating it. I have like five or six
开始吃，吃了五六口就
bites and I'm done. And only when I'm in
吃完了。只有在生
the ketogenic diet, there's something
酮饮食期间，
going on in my body which just doesn't
我的身体才会发生一些变化，
just doesn't want to binge eat like I
不再像以前那样暴饮暴食
sometimes did.
。
&gt;&gt; So there's two things to talk about. One
所以有两点需要讨论。一是生
a ketogenic diet and the other is what
酮饮食期间摄入的食物种类，二是这种饮食方式
is happening in your body in your
对身体
metabolism on the diet. So there's a a
新陈代谢的影响。有一
book called Always Hungry by a physician
本书叫《永远饥饿》（Always Hungry），作者是
u endocrinologist named David Lugwid and
内分泌学家大卫·卢格维德（David Lugwid），
he's kind of coined this carbohydrate
他提出了碳水化合物-
insulin model and um you know it's semi
胰岛素模型。这个模型虽然
somewhat controversial but the the
有些争议，但
reality is that there's there's some
确实包含一些
important notes in it. One related to
重要的信息。其中一点与
hunger which is if you're able to have a
饥饿感有关：如果你
fuel source on a ketogenic diet that's
在生酮饮食期间能够获得持续的能量来源，就
sustained over time. So you don't have
不会出现血糖波动。
downs insulin. these constant swings.
胰岛素。这些持续的波动。
Whereas on a ketogenic diet, you have
而生酮饮食则能带来
this sustained level of fuel influx,
持续的能量供应，
right? So you have this nutrient
对吧？
availability in the blood. So glucose
血液中营养物质的供应充足。因此，血糖和
levels are much more stabilized, insulin
胰岛素水平都更加稳定，
is much more stabilized, and you don't
不会出现
have those fluctuations particle.
波动。
That might be one potential reason. But
这可能是一个潜在原因。但
the other potential reason is that when
另一个潜在原因是，生
you're on a ketogenic diet, you tend to
酮饮食时，人们往往
not consume the type of foods that drive
不会摄入那些会引发
hunger. So again, we talked about in the
饥饿感的食物。我们之前提到过
grocery store, the 70% of the grocery
，超市里70%的食品
store, particularly in the center of the
，尤其是在超市中心区域，都是
grocery store that is highly processed
高度加工的，
where they combine
它们将
carbohydrates with with salt or fat or
碳水化合物与盐、脂肪或
some combination there in that makes it
其他成分混合，使其
highly palatable or very very tasty, you
口感极佳，从而
know, increase the dopamine response,
增强多巴胺反应，也就是
the food. Um, that drives people to to
食物带来的正向强化反应。这种反应会驱使人们
seek more of that pleasure response and
追求更多愉悦感，
as a result, they want to consume more.
结果就是他们想要摄入更多食物。
So, everyone has probably felt this
所以，每个人可能都有过这样的
example where you're in a restaurant,
经历：在餐厅里，
you've eaten enough food to where you
你已经吃饱了，
feel physically full. You're like, "Oh,
感觉很饱。你会想，“哦，
I'm totally full. Like, I don't want to
我吃饱了。 比如，你明明已经
eat any more food." Someone walks by
吃饱了，却还是想吃更多。
with your favorite dessert. And you're
这时，有人拿着你最爱的甜点走过，你
like, "Oh, well, h I could eat that."
心想：“哦，好吧，我可以吃点儿。”
You're literally physically full, but
你明明已经饱了，
yet you want to consume more food. This
却还想吃更多。这种
is a is a a phenomenon that has been the
现象
struggle of of in America and the the
在美国乃至
rest of the world essentially now um
全世界都普遍存在，
where the food environment often drives
食品环境常常驱使
people to over consume and it's not by
人们过度消费，这并非
accident. These are like well conducted
偶然。
strategies in the food industry to lead
食品行业精心策划了一系列策略，旨在
to these positive pleasure responses.
引发人们的愉悦感。
&gt;&gt; I think about this with bread in the
想想餐厅里的面包就
restaurant. You know they give you bread
知道了。他们总是先给你面包
first.
。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. That's a good It's a solid
没错，这确实是个好
strategy, Stephen, to cause you to want
策略，斯蒂芬，它让你想要
to consume start to finish not only the
从头到尾吃完，不仅仅是
bread, get a big meal, and follow on
面包，而是一顿丰盛的正餐，最后再来点
with dessert. You know, it it is a is a
甜点。这的确是个
is a great strategy for ensuring that,
确保你吃完的好策略，
but it's also the same strategy that,
但多力多滋（Doritos）用的也是同样的策略，他们把各种
you you combine this mixture of new uh
新的分子混合在一起，让
it, you get, oh, this tastes great.
你觉得“哦，这味道真棒”。
Pringles.
品客薯片也是
&gt;&gt; The same exact thing where you combine
如此。你把
these different components and it forces
这些不同的成分混合在一起，它会让
you this like, "Oh, this tastes great. I
你觉得，“哦，这味道真棒。”  “我还
need more." And you never feel full. One
需要更多。”你永远感觉不到饱。
food industry utilizes in these
食品行业在这种
environments is that they one they they
环境下最常用的伎俩之一就是，他们
certainly are aware of this, right? And
当然知道这一点，对吧？
so when you consume these type of foods
所以，当你同时食用这类食物时
together, they they know they consume
，他们知道自己会摄入
more of it, but sometimes people aren't
更多，但有时人们
even aware of it. And best example of
甚至没有意识到这一点。最好的例子就是
this, go look at the back of most of the
，去看看
on the grocery store aisle. Go look at
超市货架上大多数培根的背面。去看看
butters, nut butters in the grocery
超市里大多数花生酱、杏仁酱、坚果酱的背面
store. Most of them have added salt and
。它们大多都添加了盐和
added sugar. Even to levels where you
糖。甚至添加量低到你
don't even taste it, but go look at the
根本尝不出来，但去看看
label. The reason those are added is to
标签。添加这些成分的原因是为了
increase the flavor profile, the
增强风味，增强
positive brain response to the food. so
大脑对食物的积极反应，从而让
that you consume more of it. And this is
你摄入更多。这正是
a huge part in why people always feel
人们
hungry in today's food environment.
在当今的饮食环境中总是感到饥饿的重要原因之一。
They're always seeking more food
他们总是渴望更多食物，就像在
wheel. They're always over consuming or
滚轮上不停地转。他们总是过度消费，或者
always referring to this phenomenon
总是陷入一种被称为“
called food noise where they always feel
食物噪音”的现象，他们总是感到一种强烈的
the drive to consume foods or they never
进食欲望。 你永远不会
feel full. And
感到饱腹。
the soap. It is because the food is
这是因为食物中的糖分和甜味剂。食物的
composed and made in such a way to be to
成分和制作方式，是为了营造一种特定的
have a flavor profile that your brain
风味，让你的大脑
not just eat one bite, eat as much as
不满足于只吃一口，而是尽可能多地吃，
possible because we're always seeking
因为我们总是在追求
these pleasure responses, right? In our
这种愉悦感，对吧？在我们的
lives, in our world, it's this is even
生活中，在我们的世界里，这种现象甚至
independent of food.
与食物本身无关。
&gt;&gt; So, what do we do about this?
那么，我们该如何应对呢？对于
So the solution for most people in this
大多数人来说，解决办法
situation is to try to focus number one
是：首先，
don't consume liquid calories. That's
不要摄入液体卡路里。这简直是明摆着的错误之举，
like a dead giveaway bad move because
因为
those are abundance of calories
大量的液体卡路里
will drive people often to over consume
会驱使人们过量摄入，
them and very drive this pleasure
并强烈刺激
response in the brain.
大脑的愉悦反应。
&gt;&gt; Liquid calories. What's a liquid
液体卡路里是什么
calorie?
？
&gt;&gt; So let's say you have uh a soda or a
比如说，你喝了一瓶汽水或
Coke.
可乐。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So basically completely void of
是的，这些饮料几乎完全不含
any nutrients and really high in
任何营养成分，却含有极高的
calories, spikes your glucose through
卡路里，会使你的血糖和
the roof, insulin through the roof, and
胰岛素水平飙升，然后
then often makes you hungrier
往往会让你
afterwards, not less hungry by having
之后更饿，而不是像喝橙汁那样减少饥饿感
&gt;&gt; is another great example.
。
&gt;&gt; Smoothies, those those fruit smoothies
还有那些
people have.
人们常喝的水果冰沙。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. In fact, just taking fruit and
没错。事实上，仅仅是把水果榨汁，就会
then blending it up actually increases
加快
the speed by which it's absorbed changes
吸收速度，改变
the hormonal response and leads to a
激素反应，
worse outcome for most people. Most
对大多数人来说反而会适得其反。很多
people think a fruit smoothie is a
人认为水果冰沙很
healthy thing.
健康。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I don't know about that. Um, I
嗯，我对此持保留意见。嗯，
would I think that when you take fruit,
我觉得，吃水果本身没什么
which for most reasons isn't terrible,
问题，
right? Like, it's not these are
对吧？毕竟，
nutrient-dense foods, if people can
水果营养丰富，如果人们能
consume them and get away from them,
吃得健康，那就
great. If you have a metabolic disease,
很好。如果你患有代谢性疾病，
you might be more vulnerable to, let's
就更容易出现
say, glucose elevations. But when you
血糖升高之类的问题。但是，如果你把水果
then take foods like that, it could be
榨汁，或者
any foods. It could be taking potatoes
任何食物都一样，比如土豆，
and then making mashed potatoes. By
做成土豆泥，仅仅通过
simply changing or blending that food
改变或榨汁的方式
up, you're now taking a lot of the
，就去除了
structural components that your body
身体需要时间消化的许多结构成分，这就像打开
are like almost turning on like a small
一根小
hose that's just giving a little bit of
水管，
water at a time and it's turning it on
每次只放一点点水，然后突然就全部打开了一样
all the way. you know, you're rapidly
。你知道，你 它能迅速
increasing the speed of how the
加快
nutrients enter the body and it
营养物质进入人体的速度，并
completely changes the hormonal response
彻底改变
of molecules like GLP-1 and and normal
GLP-1等分子的激素反应，使
levels of GLP1 in the body are
体内正常的GLP-1水平发生
completely altered. The insulin response
彻底改变。胰岛素反应
is also altered
也会发生改变，
&gt;&gt; and GLP1 is the hunger hormone.
而GLP-1是一种饥饿激素。
&gt;&gt; It's known for being related to hunger
它因与饥饿感相关而闻名，
because it's released in response to
因为它会在
food. It changes the brain's hunger
进食后释放。它会改变大脑的饥饿
drive and most people know of it because
驱动力，大多数人了解这一点是因为
&gt;&gt; oimpic simaglletide wobi traipide um all
奥美拉唑、西咪替丁、沃比替丁等
these GLP-1 receptor agonists that
GLP-1受体激动剂，这些药物不仅能
increasing GOP1 levels not to normal
提高GLP-1水平，还能将
levels they're increasing them to super
其提高到超
physiologic levels mean levels that
生理水平，也就是在
in normal settings of the body.
正常情况下人体永远无法观察到的水平。
&gt;&gt; I've just invested millions into this
我刚刚投资了数百万美元，
and become a co-owner of the company.
成为这家公司的共同所有人。
It's a company called Ketone IQ. And the
这家公司叫Ketone IQ。它的
story is quite interesting. I started
故事非常有趣。我
talking about ketosis on this podcast
在这个播客节目中开始谈论生酮饮食，
and the fact that I'm very low carb,
事实上，我的碳水化合物和糖摄入量都非常低
very, very low sugar, and my body
，我的身体会
produces ketones, which have made me
产生酮体，这让我变得
incredibly focused, have improved my
非常专注，也改善了我的…… 它增强了
endurance, have improved my mood, and
我的耐力，改善了我的情绪，也
have made me more capable at doing what
让我更能胜任
I do here. And because I was talking
现在的工作。因为我
about it on the podcast, a couple of
在播客里提到了它，
weeks later, these showed up on my desk
几周后，这些
in my HQ in London, these little shots.
小瓶装的产品就出现在我伦敦总部的办公桌上。
And oh my god, the impact this had on my
天哪，它对我的
ability to articulate myself, on my
表达能力、专注力、
focus, on my workouts, on my mood, on
锻炼效果、情绪以及避免
stopping me crashing throughout the day
一天中精力崩溃的影响
was so profound that I reached out to
如此之大，以至于我主动联系了这家
the founders of the company, and now I'm
公司的创始人，现在我成了
a co-owner of this business. I highly,
这家公司的合伙人。我强烈
highly recommend you look into this. I
建议你了解一下。我
highly recommend you look at the science
强烈建议你研究一下
behind the product. If you want to try
这款产品背后的科学原理。如果你想
it for yourself, visit
亲自尝试，可以访问
ketone.com/stephven
ketone.com/stephven，
for 30% off your subscription order. And
订阅订单可享七折优惠。而且，
you'll also get a free gift with your
你的
second shipment. That's
第二批货还会附赠一份礼物。网址是
ketone.com/stephven.
ketone.com/stephven。
And I'm so honored that once again, a
我非常荣幸，我
company I own can sponsor my podcast.
拥有的公司能够再次赞助我的播客。
Just give me 15 seconds to explain how
请给我15秒钟的时间，让我解释一下如何在
you can build a viable business online.
网上建立一个可行的事业。
The people I see winning in life don't
我看到那些在生活中取得成功的人…… 他们
have a perfect plan. They just take the
没有完美的计划。他们只是迈出
first step and then the next and then
第一步，然后是下一步，然后坚持
they keep going. They stay obsessed and
下去。他们保持专注，并
they stay consistent. And Standtore, a
持之以恒。而
platform I co-own and one of our
我共同拥有并
sponsors, is the best first step to help
赞助的平台 Stan，正是帮助你将
turn your knowledge into income. It only
知识转化为收入的最佳第一步。
takes a couple of minutes to launch your
只需几分钟即可启动你的
business and start selling digital
业务，开始在线销售数字
products, coaching, memberships, or
产品、辅导、会员资格或
communities online without any tech
社群，无需任何技术
headaches or endless setup. Thousands of
难题或繁琐的设置。成千上万的
entrepreneurs, creators, and risktakers
企业家、创作者和冒险家
use Stan to take control of their future
使用 Stan 来掌控自己的未来，
because Stan is for entrepreneurs, for
因为 Stan 专为企业家而设，专为
those willing to put in the work and bet
那些愿意付出努力并相信
on themselves. If you're ready to start
自己的人而设。如果你准备好开始
building, join us. Launch your business
创业，那就加入我们吧。立即访问 stephvenbartlet.stan.store，
today with a free 14-day trial at
享受 14 天免费试用，开启你的事业
stephvenbartlet.stan.store.
。
So, I want to give the audience that are
所以，我想给正在
listening some practical ways that they
收听的听众一些切实可行的方法，帮助他们
can change their life to live a better
改变生活，过上更好的
life and to navigate the food
生活，并更好地应对
environment we live in. But just to just
我们所处的食品环境。但
if you had the ear of I don't know five
如果你要对五百
million people right now and you could
万人发表意见，你会给出怎样的建议呢？ 现在，你可以对
say something to them to help them live
他们说些什么，帮助他们过上
better lives, to perform better. What
更好的生活，表现得更好。
advice would you give them?
你会给他们什么建议呢？
&gt;&gt; Number one is I would say be conscious
首先，我会说要留意
you're consuming on a daily basis. The
你每天摄入的食物。
impact of food is is equivalent to
食物的影响堪比
medicine. It is and sometimes more
药物，有时甚至
powerful than medicine. So, uh what you
比药物更有效。所以，要注意你
drink, what you eat, you know, focusing
喝什么、吃什么，要
on whole foods, not consuming liquid
注重天然食物，而不是摄入液态
calories. And if you're someone who
卡路里。如果你是那种能从
could benefit uniquely from stable
稳定的
glucose levels, lower insulin levels,
血糖水平和较低的胰岛素水平中获益匪浅的人，
like someone who has some type of
比如像我一样患有某种
metabolic disorder like I do, reducing
代谢紊乱的人，那么减少
carbohydrates oftentimes can be a very
碳水化合物的摄入通常是一个非常
powerful strategy. In fact, known to
有效的策略。事实上，它已被证实可以
prevent and reverse things like obesity
预防和逆转肥胖症
and type 2 diabetes with emerging
和2型糖尿病等疾病，并且有新
evidence for its potential ability to
证据表明它有可能使
put things like serious mental illness
严重的精神疾病
into remission, but we'll see as more
得到缓解，但我们会随着更多
evidence comes out. Exercise on a
证据的出现而继续观察。
regular basis. We know that exercise
定期锻炼也很重要。我们知道，运动
exercise might not be the primary driver
可能不是导致
for why someone is or isn't obese, but
一个人肥胖或不肥胖的主要原因，但
we do know that physical activity
我们确实知道，体育锻炼
promotes health. We do know that
有益健康。
physical activity uh is extremely
嗯，这
important for overall well-being. And so
对整体健康极其重要。所以
&gt;&gt; you've got big muscles.
你肌肉很发达。
&gt;&gt; Oh, well,
哦，
&gt;&gt; is that somewhat linked to your your
这和你的
type 1 diabetes at all? Is that is that
1型糖尿病有关系吗？这是
part of your strategy? You know, look, I
你策略的一部分吗？你知道，我
was obese at one point. And so I I've
曾经很胖。所以从那时起，
since that point taken a very I become,
我就开始
you know, obsessed with trying to find
痴迷于
out how to be bigger, stronger, faster,
如何变得更大、更强壮、更快，
optimize my metabolic health, optimize
优化我的代谢健康，提升
my performance. And so it's been a
我的运动表现。所以，这对我来说就像是一场终身的自我实验
in that journey. But yeah, exercise is
。是的，运动本身就很
just important in general. But it's for
重要。但对
me it's about all the different
我来说，重要的是
experiments and and strategies I can use
我可以尝试各种不同的运动方法和策略，
with exercise uh with resistance
包括阻力
exercise and beyond to kind of play
训练等等，来探索哪些因素会
around with what affects my body, what
影响我的身体，哪些因素会
affects my insulin, how do I increase my
影响我的胰岛素水平，如何提高我的
overall metabolic health and what I have
整体代谢健康。我
seen is that that's directly linked to
发现，这与
my performance.
我的运动表现直接相关。
&gt;&gt; How often do you exercise?
你多久锻炼一次？
&gt;&gt; I try to exercise every single day. Um
我尽量每天都锻炼。嗯，每次锻炼
&gt;&gt; How long for and what types of exercise?
多久？锻炼什么类型的运动？
So what I do right now is I typically do
我现在通常的做法是…… 我
every or six days a week. Um and then I
每周大约六天，每天进行30分钟到1小时的举重训练。然后，我
will go typically ride a bike to
通常会骑自行车去练巴西
jiu-jitsu. So Brazilian jiu-jitsu which
柔术。巴西柔术是一种
can be uniquely almost like a mixed
独特的混合
exercise, intense exercise where it's
运动，强度很高，比如连续
going to be extremely intense for like 5
五
minutes and then you have a one or two
分钟强度极大，然后休息一两
minute break. Extremely intense and then
分钟。强度极大，然后
a break. Uh and I do that typically
休息。我通常
around 5 days a week. Um, I also try to
每周练五天左右。我也会尽量抽出时间进行
purposely engage in some type of aerobic
一些有氧
exercise when I can. If I I wasn't able
运动。如果某天我没能
to do as much jiu-jitsu one day or as
进行足够的柔术训练或
much uh resistance exercise. I always
力量训练，我总是会
try to add on some type of
尝试增加一些
cardiovascular work, whether that be a
有氧运动，比如
run, a bike, or these aerodyine bikes
跑步、骑自行车，或者使用那种只锻炼上下肢的有氧自行车
where it's just lower and upper body. I
。我
find those to be incredibly uh effective
发现这些运动非常有效，
and powerful tools and actually um uh
而且
just not causing damage to muscle tissue
不仅不会损伤肌肉组织，还能
but also allowing you to improve your
改善
overall cardiovascular health.
整体心血管健康。
&gt;&gt; What does your diet look like?
你的饮食习惯是怎样的？
&gt;&gt; So I tend to wake up and not think about
我通常早上醒来…… 醒来后不去想吃
food. That's one thing that I've also
东西。这一点我和
experienced similar to you that when I
你也有类似的经历。当我
switched to a ketogenic diet, not only
开始生酮饮食后，不仅
improve my glucose and insulin, but I
血糖和胰岛素水平有所改善，而且我
also found that with a ketogenic diet
发现生酮饮食让
that I
我
don't feel hungry. So, I would wake up
感觉不到饥饿。所以，我醒来后通常
and I don't tend to eat food right away.
不会马上吃东西。
In fact,
事实上，
I enjoy when I don't eat food more so
我常常更喜欢不吃东西的状态，而不是
than when I do eat food often times just
吃东西的状态。这
because not because I don't enjoy the
并不是说我不喜欢
feeling of sitting down and having food.
坐下来享用美食的感觉——
I love that.
我很喜欢那种感觉。
But
而是因为我享受到了
of not having high variable glucose
没有高血糖
levels, high insulin levels, and the
、高胰岛素水平波动以及由此
uncertainty that comes with that in my
带来的不确定性的生活质量。
daily life, I enjoy the 23 hours or 22
我享受一天中那22或23个
hours of my day where I have the
小时的
stability, not the the moments in time
稳定状态，而不是那些充满不
where I'm introducing uncertainty and
确定性和
variability.
波动的时刻。
to dumb that down a little bit. What I'm
简单来说，
saying is that when I when I don't eat I
就是当我
wake up and I don't eat food because I
醒来后不吃东西时，我
find that it I'm not hungry, but I also
发现自己不饿，而且我
find that it makes managing diabetes
发现这样更容易控制糖尿病
easier.
。
&gt;&gt; And so, do you eat once a day or twice a
所以，你是每天吃一顿还是两顿？
day or
我一般一天吃两到三顿，
you know, sometimes right before
你知道，有时候是在练
jiu-jitsu or weightlifting jiu-jitsu,
柔术或举重柔术之前，练完
always afterwards and always before uh
之后总是会吃，而且总是在睡前吃，
sometimes before bed. try not to do it
有时候也会在睡前吃。尽量不要
right before bed um because it tends to
在睡前吃，因为它会
impact my sleep quality a little bit.
影响我的睡眠质量。
But I find that I just eat whenever I
我发现我只要饿了就吃，
feel hungry and I try to give myself
而且我会尽量摄入
sufficient protein to be able to respond
足够的蛋白质，以便能够应对
to the the exercise that I'm doing.
我正在进行的锻炼。
&gt;&gt; So, I've got the first one's about being
所以，第一点是关于有
intentional about your food choices. The
意识地选择食物。
second one is about exercise.
第二点是关于锻炼。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。还有
&gt;&gt; Anything else?
什么吗？
&gt;&gt; Well, sleep's really important. You
嗯，睡眠真的很重要。你
know, these are these are, you know,
知道，
Stephen, this isn't like uh oh, like
斯蒂芬，这并不是什么惊天动地的
this is the most revolutionary advice of
革命性建议
all time, but these these core
，但这些核心
foundational components, good nutrition
基础要素——
tailored to your specific needs,
根据你的具体需求量身定制的良好营养、
exercising as much as you can, and
尽可能多地锻炼以及
getting good sleep are the pillars of
充足的睡眠——是
health. If you don't have those
健康的支柱。如果你没有
corrected, then you're wasting your time
纠正这些，那么你就是在浪费时间。 其他
everywhere else. And is there anything
地方的情况也一样。
as it relates to glucose
关于血糖，有没有什么让
that surprised you? Because you're
你感到惊讶的？因为你经常
someone that sees a lot of this data. I
接触这类数据。我的
mean, you you you you walk around with
意思是，你带着
the the the two devices on that you've
你提到的那两个设备到处走，
mentioned and you're you're looking at
观察
the insulin and glucose response. Is
胰岛素和血糖的反应。
there anything that people don't
有没有什么食物，人们
understand as having a really pronounced
不了解，却会对血糖水平产生非常显著的
impact on their glucose levels that they
影响，而这是他们
wouldn't expect? Like orange juice is
意想不到的？比如橙汁，
one of the ones that growing up I
我小时候
thought [__] I thought this was a
觉得这
healthy thing. I used to I used to drink
玩意儿很健康。我以前经常喝
Sunny Delight thinking I was putting all
Sunny Delight，觉得这样能补充各种
these amazing vitamins in my body
维生素，
&gt;&gt; and now I actually look back and regret
现在回想起来真是后悔。
it and I you know
我知道我
&gt;&gt; not to be judgmental over any parents
不想评判任何父母，
because parenting is very hard but
因为养育孩子很辛苦，但
sometimes I'll see parents giving their
有时候我会看到父母给
children like a big glass of orange
孩子喝一大杯
juice and in my head I just see the
橙汁，我脑子里就会浮现出
glucose spike that that child's about to
孩子血糖飙升的画面
have. It's funny when you mention
。说到
parenting because I have a three and a
养育孩子，我觉得很有意思，因为我家也有两个孩子，一个三岁，一个
six-year-old at home and it's amazing
六岁。
when they try one of these foods, these
当他们尝试这些食物，这些
very sugary foods, these very tasty
非常甜、非常美味的食物时，他们的反应真是令人惊叹。
foods, they
食物，他们
it's almost like they become incessant
几乎会不停地
on wanting it again. You know, like
想要再次食用。你知道，就像
normal food isn't good enough anymore.
普通的食物已经无法满足他们的需求了。
Um,
嗯，
and I think that's a great illustration
我认为这很好地说明了
of of what many of us adults are are
我们许多成年人
challenged with on a daily basis, but
每天都面临的挑战，但
yet many people are just unaware of the
很多人却没有意识到
impact that it's having on their
这会对他们的
metabolism, impacting it's having on
新陈代谢、
their hunger, the impact that that's
饥饿感以及
going to lead to on their future health.
未来的健康造成怎样的影响。
&gt;&gt; And is there anything that you've
你使用动态
your CGM and your insulin device that
血糖监测仪和胰岛素泵进行的实验中，有没有发现什么
people should most certainly avoid? So,
人们应该绝对避免的食物？
you said liquid calories. Is there
你刚才提到了液体卡路里。还有什么
anything else that causes a really
其他食物会导致非常
pronounced or unexpected glucose
明显或意想不到的血糖
response? Yeah, you know, there's so
反应吗？是的，
many honestly, Stephen, over time that
斯蒂芬，说实话，随着时间的推移，有很多食物会导致这种情况，所以
it's honest, it's really hard to
很难
pinpoint any singular one. A lot of the
指出哪一种是罪魁祸首。很多
foods that are out there are often
食物，尤其是加工食品，往往会对
surprisingly challenging on glucose
血糖和胰岛素水平造成意想不到的挑战，
the processed foods, because what
因为在
happens when you make these food
生产这些
products is that you're trusting the
食品的过程中，你信任
food company to put ingredients in there
食品公司会添加各种成分。 里面有些东西
that you're going to respond favorably
你肯定会有好反应
to, that your metabolism will respond
，你的新陈代谢也会对它们反应
well to. And the truth is that that's
良好。但事实是，这
far from a guarantee and in many cases
远非绝对，在很多情况下，这种可能性甚至比
maybe uh less likely than it is likely.
想象的要小。
And so yeah, I don't have a singular
所以，斯蒂芬，我没有一个具体的
example for you, Stephen. I just But
例子可以给你，但
I've experienced it numerous times.
我有很多次亲身经历。
&gt;&gt; So I've got a a small list here. Um
我这里列个小清单：
sugary drinks, white bread and bagels,
含糖饮料、白面包和百吉饼、
white rice. That surprised me a lot cuz
白米饭。这让我很惊讶，因为
I used to think white rice Oh, really? I
我以前一直觉得白米饭……哦，真的吗？我从小就觉得
I thought growing up rice was like a
米饭是
health food.
健康食品。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Well, so on that note,
好吧。说到
white rice, potatoes,
白米饭，还有土豆，
potatoes in any form.
任何形式的土豆。
&gt;&gt; Sweet potatoes tend to have less of a
红薯的
glycemic response, but it's still going
血糖反应相对较小，但仍然会引发
to have a a potent glycemic response.
强烈的血糖反应。
&gt;&gt; So, mashed or baked potatoes, obviously,
所以，土豆泥或烤土豆，当然还有
French fries. Yeah,
炸薯条。没错，
&gt;&gt; for sure. French fries. Most of like
绝对是炸薯条。大多数意大利面
pasta is a big one.
也是一大类。
&gt;&gt; Cereal,
谷物，尤其是
refined cereals,
精制谷物，
&gt;&gt; most cereals are actually worse than the
大多数谷物
foods I just described on blood sugar
对血糖和胰岛素的影响实际上比我刚才提到的那些食物要糟糕
and insulin by a long shot. In fact, uh
得多。 事实上，
mo most of the you know these
你知道，大多数这些所谓的“有益
hearthealthy cereals um
心脏健康的谷物”，嗯，
these these would I would never blood
这些，我从来不会吃，因为它们会让
sugar would just spike through the roof
血糖飙升到
portion of the amount I ate. So yeah, it
我吃掉的那部分。所以，是的，
it I wouldn't I wouldn't be consuming a
我不会吃
lot of those. And I think I think most
太多。而且我认为，
people at this stage in the the health
在健康
and science world would also generally
和科学领域，大多数人也普遍
align with with that that those aren't
认同这一点，即这些
necessarily the best foods to consume.
食物未必是最佳选择。
we would think, you know, more more of
我们认为，应该多吃一些
the less glycemic or less the foods that
低升糖指数的食物，或者那些对
have less of an impact on glucose
血糖和
levels, less of a impact on insulin
胰岛素水平影响较小的食物
levels. You know, one one thing I
。你知道，我
constantly hear, especially in the
经常听到的一种说法，尤其是在
research and clinical community is like,
研究和临床领域，是这样的：
well, look, you know, not everyone needs
你看，不是每个人都需要
to be concerned about that because, you
担心这个问题，因为
know, people can respond to a lot of
很多人对
these foods just fine. And I say,
这些食物的反应都很好。我说：
"You're you're right." Except that over
“你说得对。”但问题是，超过
half of America has pre-diabetes
一半的美国人患有糖尿病前期，超过
and 90 plus% have some form of
90%的人的某些指标
measurement that indicates that their
显示他们的
metabolic health is impaired and over 86
代谢健康受损，超过
68% are obese and now children are
86%的人患有糖尿病。 肥胖症，现在儿童也深受
obesity and pre-diabetes and around 20%.
肥胖和糖尿病前期等疾病的困扰，患病率高达20%左右。
So it it's it's the fact that we are now
所以，我们现在的
less healthy than than we've ever been.
健康状况比以往任何时候都差。
Um
嗯，
&gt;&gt; we don't have the foundation to support.
我们没有足够的健康基础来支撑。
&gt;&gt; Correct. And I think you know when we
没错。我想，当我们
think about healthy nutrition, we think
想到健康营养时，我们就会想到
about exercise.
运动。
We describe them as medicine, but the
我们把运动比作良药，但
reality is these are just normal aspects
实际上，这些只是我们
of things you should do every single day
每天都应该做的正常事情，
because that's what our bodies were made
因为我们的身体本来就应该这样
to do. And when we don't do those
做。当我们不做这些
things, this is when health
事情时，健康状况就会
deteriorates. This is when we're
恶化。当我们不做这些事情时，
challenging our body to maintain normal
我们的身体就难以维持正常的
health.
健康状态。让
&gt;&gt; One of the surprising ones for me was
我感到惊讶的是，
dried fruit. And it said while while
干果。文章指出，虽然
fruit contains natural sugars, the
水果含有天然糖分，但
process of drying it concentrates those
干燥过程会浓缩这些
sugars. This removes the water and can
糖分。这会去除水分，
make the sugar more readily available
使糖分更容易被
for absorption, leading to a higher
吸收，从而导致
glucose spike compared to fresh fruit.
血糖​​飙升幅度比新鲜水果更高。
Typically, people think of dried fruit
通常，人们也认为干果
as being a health food as well.
是健康食品。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I don't I don't touch those
是的。我不会碰干果，
because unless I I don't have any
因为除非我
glucose on me and I my blood sugar is
身上没有葡萄糖。 如果我的血糖
going down for some reason and I stay in
因为某种原因下降，并且一直处于
dangerously low levels, that's when I
危险的低水平，我才会
consume those foods. Otherwise, I would
吃这些食物。否则，
I would not consume them just because of
我不会吃，因为
how quickly they raise blood sugar
它们会迅速升高血糖
levels.
。
&gt;&gt; Do you think everybody should try the
你认为每个人都应该尝试
ketogenic diet?
生酮饮食吗？
&gt;&gt; Ooh, that is a good question. I think
哦，这真是个好问题。
What I would say is that you will never
我想说的是，如果你不尝试，就永远不会
know the potential of its benefit or
知道它的潜在益处或
lack thereof if you don't try. Like
弊端。就像
anything in life, we are we're left to
生活中的其他事情一样，我们只能
assume what everyone else is like. You
假设其他人的情况。
ketogenic diet numerous times here. We
我们在这里已经多次讨论过生酮饮食，也多次
talked about exogenous ketones numerous
讨论过外源性酮
times here.
。
But if you don't try it, you don't know
但如果你不尝试，你就不知道
how it'll work for you. In science,
它对你的效果如何。在科学领域，
Stephen, one of the most important
斯蒂芬，最重要的一点
things to appreciate is that we often
是，我们经常
publish bar graphs look like this. You
发表的柱状图看起来是这样的。你
know, the a line uh that illustrates the
知道，一条线代表了
average outcome of a group of people.
一组人的平均结果。
But what you don't appreciate is that
但你可能没有意识到，
that line or that bar graph is made up
这条线或柱状图是由
of numerous individuals who all average
许多个体组成的，他们的平均值都等于
to that number. But what if you're the
这个数字。但是，如果你……
person who's at the very high dot or the
处于最高点或
very bottom dot, meaning that you're the
最低点的人，也就是所谓的
what they call an outlier or someone who
异常值，或者说
responded negatively or positively to
对研究结果反应相反（负面或正面）的人，
that and then you just follow the
然后你只是遵循了
average advice that that study showed.
那项研究给出的平均建议。
Well, oh, look, I tried this approach
好吧，你看，我试过这种方法，
and it didn't it didn't work for me. Uh,
但对我没用。呃，
I'm just going to keep trying cuz this
我还是继续尝试吧，因为这项
study said that I should. Well, no. you
研究说我应该这样做。嗯，不。你
might be the person who was in that
可能就是那项
study who didn't respond just like the
研究中没有反应的人，就像
person on the opposite end of the
处于光谱另一端、反应良好的人一样，他们的
spectrum who did who averaged out to the
平均值被拉到了
metal.
中间。
&gt;&gt; So when in that study that talked about
所以，在那项讨论
the impact of exogenous ketones on brain
外源性酮对大脑
stability, someone might have had 100%
稳定性影响的研究中，有些人可能
improvement in brain stability and
大脑稳定性提高了100%，
someone might have had 20% improvement
有些人可能提高了20%
or whatever and they've averaged it out
或其他数值，研究人员将这些数据
um across a bigger group of people. So
在更大样本群体中取平均值。所以，
if you you are that person that had a
如果你是
100% gain in brain stability, it's a
大脑稳定性提高100%的那一个人，那么根据你的身体状况来理解，这确实是一个
pretty unbelievable tool for you to
非常不可思议的工具。
&gt;&gt; Exactly. And and that's that's always
没错。
the case in science. I mean there are
科学研究总是如此。我的意思是，
and there sometimes we look at this as
有时我们会把受试者分为
responders and non-responders. Um but
反应者和无反应者。嗯，但
actually in the study where we gave um
实际上，在我们进行的SOCOM研究中，当受试者服用
uh the product from ketone IQ in the the
酮体IQ产品时，
SOCOM study, we actually saw that nearly
我们发现几乎
all of them saw an increase in SPO2.
所有受试者的血氧饱和度（SpO2）都有所升高。
nearly all themselves an increase in
几乎所有受试者的
heart rate but that's rare that is rare
心率也有所升高，但心率升高的情况比较少见。血氧饱和度（
&gt;&gt; sp2
SpO2）是指
&gt;&gt; ah so uh the amount of oxygen in the
血液中的氧气含量，它可以
indicate whether someone
用来衡量
&gt;&gt; uh in these low oxygen environments had
在低氧环境下，
more blood or less more oxygen or less
血液中的氧气含量是高还是低。
&gt;&gt; ultimately it's it's important to try I
最终，尝试不同的营养策略非常重要。
I think it's I would always say yes you
我认为我总是会说，你
should try because or any nutrition
应该尝试，
strategy because you should try
因为你应该尝试
different ones I've probably tried over
不同的策略。我可能已经尝试过不止一种了。 说
plus different diets only honestly maybe
实话，我现在这辈子可能只租房吃减肥餐，大概
like 15 or 20 at this point in my life.
15到20次吧。
I've just come to find that the
我发现，由于
ketogenic diet for all the reasons we
我们描述的所有原因，加上
described and because I have type 1
我患有 1 型
diabetes and I had obese or have type 1
糖尿病并且曾经肥胖，
find that a ketogenic diet is remarkably
生酮饮食
powerful at helping me live a
在帮助我显著
dramatically improved quality of life.
改善生活质量方面非常有效。
not have the increased risk for the high
不会增加
invariable glucose levels, high insulin
血糖水平持续偏高、胰岛素
levels that lead to a a near guarantee
水平偏高的风险，而这些风险几乎肯定会导致
of complications and 10 to 20 years of
并发症，并造成 10 到 20 年的
lost life and expectancy. That's why I
寿命和预期寿命损失。 这就是我这么做的原因
do it.
。
&gt;&gt; I have a closing tradition on this
在这个播客节目中，我有一个结尾的传统，
podcast where the next guest leaves a
那就是下一位嘉宾会给
question for the next guest not knowing
下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，但他并不知道这个问题是
who they're leaving it for. And this is
留给谁的。 这是
a really tough question.
一个非常棘手的问题。
&gt;&gt; So, it's a very strange question as
所以，这也是个很奇怪的问题
well, but I'm going to ask you it
，但我还是要问你
anyway.
。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. The question is
。 问题是，
what is outside the simulation?
模拟之外是什么？
I think it depends on your philosophy
我认为这取决于你对
on how our existence
我们存在的哲学
of understanding that our awareness of
理解，即我们对
our world is completely limited to our
世界的认知完全受限于我们
our brain's capacity and
大脑的容量、
our interpretation and then explanation
我们对
of the world and the term of a
世界的解释和诠释，以及对
simulation or lack, you know, however
模拟或缺失的理解——无论
you want to frame it, I believe is is
你怎么定义它——我相信它
always going to be limited by our
始终会受到我们
brain's ability to understand and
大脑理解和
articulate that.
表达能力的限制。
&gt;&gt; So, what do you think is outside the
那么，你认为模拟之外还有哪些东西
simulation?
？
&gt;&gt; Consciousness.
意识。
&gt;&gt; You think consciousness is outside the
你认为意识存在于
simulation? I think that
模拟之外吗？ 我认为，
Stephen, but our ability to
斯蒂芬，我们拥有的能力并非意识本身，而是
operate beyond
超越
consciousness.
意识的能力。
&gt;&gt; Got me on that one, man. That was a that
这话我可信了，老兄。 那真是个
&gt;&gt; tough question.
棘手的问题。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it is a tough question. That's
是的，这确实是个棘手的问题。 那就是，那就是，那就是，那就是，那
that's that's a it's a burner right
是个燃烧器
there. I don't know. Do do you think
。 我不知道。 你认为在
we see here?
我们所看到的一切之外，是否存在一个神？
&gt;&gt; I'm going to give you the most real
我会给你最真实、最
honest answer possible.
诚恳的回答。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; I don't think we ever can actually
我认为我们永远无法
answer that question accurately.
准确回答这个问题。
&gt;&gt; So your your answer therefore is you
所以你的答案是：你
don't know.
不知道。
&gt;&gt; I don't know and I don't think I'll ever
我不知道，而且我觉得我永远也不会
know.
知道。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Okay.
。 好的。
Thank you. Thank you so much for doing
谢谢。 非常感谢你
the work that you do. really appreciate
所做的工作。 非常感谢，
that because you know so many of my
因为我认识的很多
friends in this field and even Michael
在这个领域的朋友，甚至我桌上这款
the founder of the the ketone product on
酮类产品的创始人迈克尔，都把
my on my uh table here talk about you as
你视为
leadership on the subject of ketones and
酮类研究科学和思想领导力的黄金标准，
more broadly on the subject of um
更广泛地说，在
glucose and all of the adjacent subjects
葡萄糖以及所有相关领域（
like insulin. So you've really pushed
如胰岛素）也是如此。 所以你确实以一种非常深刻的方式推动了
forward in this space in a really
该领域的发展和思维进步，
profound way and you're only just
而你才
getting started at 34 years old which is
34岁，这真是
remarkable. we're basically the same age
令人瞩目。 我们年龄差不多，
and uh you've had such a tremendous
而且你
impact on the field of health and that's
对健康领域产生了巨大的影响，这源于
born out of the story that you told at
你一
the start through your own
开始讲述的你自己的
complications. So although it was it's
并发症的故事。 虽然
diagnosis at such a young age, what's
在如此年轻的时候被诊断出患有这样的疾病是一件非常悲惨的事情，但这件事也带来了
come from that is a beautiful thing for
一件美好的结果，那就是让
so many people um that will better
很多人更好地
understand themselves and their their
了解自己和自己的
illnesses but also their performance and
疾病，以及他们的表现和
um everything correlate related to that
所有与之相关的事物，这都归功于
because of you. So please keep doing the
你。 所以请继续进行
research you're doing and spreading the
你正在进行的研究，并以
word in the way you're spreading it
你现在的方式传播信息，
because it's much much needed work and
因为这是一项非常必要且
it's it's important work. So, thank you
重要的工作。 非常感谢你，
so much and thank you for giving me your
也感谢你
time today,
今天抽出时间接受我的采访，
&gt;&gt; Stephen. That was an honor. Appreciate
斯蒂芬。 那是一种荣幸。 谢谢你
it, sir.
，先生。
&gt;&gt; Make sure you keep what I'm about to say
请务必将我接下来要说的话保密
to yourself. I'm inviting 10,000 of you
。 我邀请你们中的 10,000 人
to come even deeper into the diary of a
更深入地了解一位 CEO 的日记
CEO. Welcome to my inner circle. This is
。 欢迎来到我的核心圈子。 这是
a brand new private community that I'm
我即将向全世界推出的一个全新的私人社区
launching to the world. We have so many
。 我们这里发生了很多
incredible things that happen that you
不可思议的事情，但你却
are never shown. We have the briefs that
从未见过。
are on my iPad when I'm recording the
我在录制对话时，iPad 上会显示一些简要说明
conversation. We have clips we've never
。 我们有一些从未
released. We have behindthe-scenes
公开过的视频片段。 我们有
conversations with the guests and also
与嘉宾的幕后对话，还有
the episodes that we've never ever
从未
released and so much more. In the
发布过的剧集等等。 在这个
circle, you'll have direct access to me.
圈子里，你可以直接联系到我。
You can tell us what you want this show
您可以告诉我们您希望这个节目
to be, who you want us to interview, and
成为什么样子，您希望我们采访谁，以及
the types of conversations you would
您
love us to have. But remember, for now,
希望我们进行哪些类型的对话。 但请记住，目前
we're only inviting the first 10,000
我们只邀请前 10,000 名
people that join before it closes. So,
加入的人，活动即止。 所以，
if you want to join our private closed
如果您想加入我们的私人封闭
community, head to the link in the
社区，请点击
description below or go to
下方说明中的链接或访问
daccircle.com.
daccircle.com。   到时候
I will speak to you then.
我再跟你谈。
[Music]
[音乐]
Heat. Heat.
热浪。热。